<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[This is Colin McCloskey]]></title>
  <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-28T19:49:11-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://mccolin.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Colin McCloskey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breathing New Life Into an Old Thing]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2013/12/28/breathing-new-life-into-an-old-thing/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-28T16:59:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2013/12/28/breathing-new-life-into-an-old-thing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So&hellip; it turns out I have a personal website. And you are currently reading it. And it also turns
out that I haven&rsquo;t contributed interesting content to this site &mdash; apart from a résumé update or
two &mdash; since my birthday nearly two years ago.</p>

<p>So&hellip; I&rsquo;ve decided (once again) to put new effort into this place. There are lot of things
going on in my life that are worth talking about &mdash; mostly for my own self reflection purposes, but
no doubt for the benefit of some of you reading. I&rsquo;ve used writing and reflection in the past as
a way to deal with change and challenges and that seems like a good thing for me to be doing as
we head into 2014. <!--more--></p>

<p>What life changes and challenges, you ask!? Well&hellip;</p>

<ul>
<li>I&rsquo;m going to be a dad. <a href="http://thebluesunshine.com/">Liz</a> and I are expecting our first child together, due in early
March of next year. The whole endeavor fills me with joy and excitement, but also questions,
concerns, and worries.</li>
<li>I run <a href="http://awexomelabs.com/">my own solo-employed business</a>. This makes me keen to share thoughts and strategies
for &ldquo;businessy&rdquo; things I&rsquo;m doing.</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m going to be 31 years old, soon, and that means I&rsquo;ll be undeniably <em>in my thirties</em>. This
means I&rsquo;m doing lots more &ldquo;grownup&rdquo; and &ldquo;adult&rdquo; things with my time and my tastes are changing.
That makes for mildly interesting writing, yes?</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m getting into new things like cooking and organizing and projects and more. I think sharing
those things about one&rsquo;s self is important.</li>
</ul>


<p>So, to start, I&rsquo;ve redesigned the site (you are currently using your eyeballs to experience that
change) and <a href="http://mccolin.github.io/about/">I&rsquo;ve updated the &ldquo;About Me&rdquo; page on this site</a>. It&rsquo;s got new facts, new stories,
and more than before you can learn about me and my life. And beyond that, I&rsquo;m going to aim to
contribute here more often than I obviously have over the past few years. We&rsquo;ll see if I can keep
up a pace, but the intention is there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[29th Anniversary]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2012/01/23/29th-anniversary/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2012/01/23/29th-anniversary</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today will mark 29 years since the end of the B.C. (&#8220;Before Colin&#8221;) calendar and the beginning of the current and amazing A.D. (&#8220;Awesome Days&#8221;) period.</p>

<p>You&#8217;re welcome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stuffed Portobello Mushroom Caps]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/10/19/stuffed-portobello-mushroom-caps/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/10/19/stuffed-portobello-mushroom-caps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here I am, at it again! Cooking!</p>

<p>This recipe is a basic, tasty dish that uses a protein I wasn&#8217;t familiar with, personally, but which is a treat to many before me: the portobello mushroom. This dish is one notch away from being vegetarian &#8212; one deliciously wonderful notch. So, you&#8217;re able to modify this to suit a few different dietary needs.</p>

<p>Plus, it&#8217;s frakkin&#8217; delicious and easy to make in about 15 minutes.</p>

<p>You should pick up:</p>

<ul>
<li>Portobello Mushroom Caps &#8212; often sold is a store-wrapped package at your grocer. <a href="http://www.bluefeathermedia.com/index/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/Portobello-Mushroom.jpg">They look like this</a>.</li>
<li>1 tbsp Extra Virgin Olive Oil</li>
<li>1 to 2 Garlic Cloves (depending on how garlic&#8217;y you like things), peeled and minced</li>
<li>1 Red Bell Pepper, cut into strips (you can sub in a green pepper if you&#8217;re stuck, but red or orange peppers are the best &#8212; you should know this already)</li>
<li>Strips of Bacon (one for each mushroom cap)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.mccormick.com/Products/GrillMates/Seasoning-Blends/Grill-Mates-Spicy-Montreal-Steak-Seasoning.aspx">Montreal Steak Spicy seasoning</a> (you can use pepper and red pepper flakes if you want to get close)</li>
<li>Salt (don&#8217;t measure your salt, just go with what feels right)</li>
<li>Shredded Parmesan Cheese (this is a topping, so have enough to top your caps)</li>
<li>Shredded Mozzarella Cheese (also for our cheesy topping)</li>
</ul>


<p>Got it all? Ready to go? Nice. Let&#8217;s continue!</p>

<ol>
<li>Heat the olive oil in a medium skillet over medium heat. Stir in the garlic and peppers. Season with salt. Cook uncovered for a couple minutes, and then&#8230;</li>
<li>Add strips of bacon to the skillet. I find placing them around the edges is best. Continue cooking 2 to 3 minutes until peppers are tender. While tenderizing your peppers&#8230;</li>
<li>Prepare your mushroom caps by first washing them, then drizzle some olive oil on and in the gills (the underside). Season the underside to taste with Montreal Steak (or your pepper substitute) and a bit a salt.</li>
<li>Now, flip the bacon and add your mushroom caps to the center of the skillet, cooking the underside first. Reduce heat to low-medium, cover and cook for about 5 minutes. Your kitchen is going to start smelling really great about now, if it doesn&#8217;t already.</li>
<li>After 5 minutes or so, flip the bacon and mushrooms once more. Layer both shredded cheese on the mushrooms (you are applying the cheese to the seasoned underside of the mushrooms). Cover it up again and cook for another 5 minutes, until tender.</li>
<li>Now it&#8217;s ready! Remove from heat and plate! Take each cheesy mushroom cap off the skillet, then cover each with your pepper/garlic reduction. Put a strip of bacon on top and it&#8217;s good-to-go delicious!</li>
</ol>


<p>It looks like more work than it is. Total prep and cook time should be about 15-20 minutes. And it&#8217;s worth it. The bacon fat helps the peppers and garlic reach a state of &#8220;more awesome than usual&#8221; without robbing the dish of its healthiness.</p>

<p>I suggest you serve beside <a href="http://www.neareast.com/#products/tomato_lentil">Tomato Lentil Couscous</a>, which is a great compliment.</p>

<p>Wow! Colin cooked up mushrooms!</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Memory]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/09/11/memory/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/09/11/memory</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;">
  SEPTEMBER 11th, 2001<br /> as remembered on<br /> SEPTEMBER 11th, 2011
</p>


<p>I was waking up. Earlier than usual, because I had a class to get to. It was barely the third week of college and I was in Room 103 of Russell Hall E at the University of Delaware. My roommate &#8211;now one of my closest friends, but then still someone I was getting to know&#8211; and I were awoken by our neighbor, Adam from Room 105, banging on our door telling us to turn on the news.</p>

<p>We had the largest TV on the floor, which is funny considering it was a mere 25in. TV/VCR combo. As a result, a handful of friends and floormates gathered in our room. I was watching the havoc unfold and watching live when the second plane struck.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Everything was mesmerizing. Stunning. Awesome. It all seemed so big. Here I was in a room, in a dorm, at a college, and in a state I had known for shy of three weeks, surrounded by a half-dozen or so young adults in the same situation. We didn&#8217;t know what to do. We were paralyzed by the news and by the bigness of it all.</p>

<p>I went to class. I&#8217;m sure I could&#8217;ve skipped, but I was a Freshman away from home, confused about everything happening, and desperate to insert some rhythm, schedule, and routine back into this day of destruction. I remember walking to class and wondering if the other students around me knew what was going on. It was obvious that some did. It was also strikingly obvious that many did not. I learned through the four years of college that followed how routine it can be for a college student to roll right out of bed and on to class. This explains why so many people seemed to have no idea of the news, but I remember it feeling so very odd to me at the time.</p>

<p>What I remember most about that walk to class &#8211;and that morning in general&#8211; is the sky. As a whole, the weather that day was the type of autumnal weather you yearn for &#8212; a bright, blue sky full of fluffy, white clouds accompanied by a light, but crisp breeze. Had it not been for everything unfolding in New York, and later Pennsylvania and Washington, it might have been the most beautiful day of the year.</p>

<p>My 9:30AM class did not start as had been its usual. People were talking about the news throughout the beginning of class and the professor, frustrated, asked what was going on. A student told him what had happened. He turned on the television in the classroom and we watched a bit more of things on CNN. Eventually, he started our linguistics discussion up again, but class was a bit more broken than before.</p>

<p>After class, I returned to my dorm. Along the way, I had a conversation with a new friend from my class who would become my sophomore year roommate and a part of my core group of friends throughout college. I don&#8217;t remember any specifics, but I remember standing for a bit on the South Mall, near Allison Hall, talking about the events of the day and the weather.</p>

<p>Once back at the dorm, there were a lot of people stirring, watching the news, reading things online, and gathering. The news of Pennsylvania and the Pentagon crashes was now out. For a brief while I thought everything and everyone in America might be in danger. Some of us were too shocked to really understand what it all meant, others were altogether too angry and patriotic, storming about the place.</p>

<p>I remember trying to call my parents, but having a hard time getting any connection on my cell phone. A group of us must&#8217;ve went to lunch around this time, but I don&#8217;t remember it.</p>

<p>I was able to checkin on other friends at college through Instant Messenger. People posted status messages indicating that they were unharmed and safe. Several of my closest friends attended school in New York and near Washington. All were okay. It was amazing to be so connected to people throughout the day, and realizing how similarly we all felt. New friends I&#8217;d met at school and old friends away at their own schools, all trying to figure things out and understand what and why.</p>

<p>In my afternoon class, an honors English course with a professor I had already come to abhor, we had fairly high attendance. One girl in our class was clearly affected by the tragedies personally. She was being consoled by friends and the professor. I remember only that this girl was a commuting student and that in coming weeks, she would leave our class, presumably due to family difficulties stemming from the tragedy. As I remember this, I wish I had been one of the students to console her, but I had a very &#8220;deer in headlights&#8221; approach to the day in general, and did not. In the class, we postponed our planned discussion and instead talked about the days&#8217; events. It was interesting to have the thoughts of about twenty eighteen year olds scrambled into a discussion, but everything was so raw or shallow. It takes time to figure out how you feel about things like this, and we&#8217;d only had about five hours. I didn&#8217;t know how to summarize everything I was feeling weeks later, let alone hours.</p>

<p>In the early evening I did get in touch with my parents. My Mom and Dad were distraught and upset like everyone else I&#8217;d interacted with that day. I talked with them on my cell phone, which I&#8217;d only had for a few weeks, on the grass outside my dorm and dining hall. I remember exactly where, though a year later, the university would rip up the pavement and trees, changing that area of campus entirely. I remember my Dad telling me to be calm and take everything in. I was already calm, but at this point in the day mostly confused. There wasn&#8217;t really a good way to fight the confusion.</p>

<p>My girlfriend at the time was still in high school. We were able to talk that evening. It was her sister&#8217;s birthday. I remember, clearly, my girlfriend cursing that it was a &#8220;pretty shitty birthday present, huh?&#8221; which was striking because she so rarely used language like that. It was a small outburst, but really indicative of what everyone was going through that day. She told me how upsetting it had been to learn of everything going on in school and I wished so very much to be wherever she was. There is something about tragedy that makes you <em>need</em> to be with the people you love, and I felt that intensely that evening. A big part of me just wanted to be home.</p>

<p>As day finally turned into night, the dorm was still abuzz with activity and life. That&#8217;s normal for a dorm full of freshman, but it was different. Quiet hours were actually pretty quiet, but you could clearly hear conversations and the noise of news broadcasts on televisions in each room. There wasn&#8217;t any of the fairly typical hall sports or rambunctious behavior in the hallway.</p>

<p>I can&#8217;t remember dinner, which is funny, because I can&#8217;t seem to remember a single meal from that day. I can&#8217;t remember many details beyond the morning. I remember large swaths of feelings, and the gorgeous weather. I don&#8217;t remember when or how I was able to fall asleep with so much running around in my head, but I remember hoping the next day would be better. I hoped the next day would bring more information and reason into the ambush of excitement and fear that plagued today…</p>

<p>&#8212;</p>

<p>In the ten years since, I have graduated college, entered the working world, moved across the country (by plane, of course), moved back across the country, married my lovely wife (one of my closest friends from that dorm Freshman year), and started my own business.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve been through more trying times, personally, than September 11th, but nothing since has come close in terms of national spectacle than the events of that day. It was shaping up to be a beautiful, perfect autumn day until around 9:00am when everything changed.</p>

<p>I can&#8217;t believe it&#8217;s been ten years.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mom&#8217;s Shrimp Salad]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/07/04/moms-shrimp-salad/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/07/04/moms-shrimp-salad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Perfect for a warm summer day. Not a salad you&#8217;ve added shrimp to, but a chilled pasta and shrimp sensation! Plus, there&#8217;s mayonnaise, so it&#8217;s extra indulgent&#8230; yes, that&#8217;s the word I&#8217;m going for&#8230; indulgent.</p>

<p>You will need:</p>

<ul>
<li>2 cans of Tiny shrimp (Bumble Bee brand is great, substitute Small if your grocer does not have Tiny)</li>
<li>1 lb. box of Medium (or Small) Shell Pasta</li>
<li>1 onion (sweet or not, pick your poison)</li>
<li>Some celery (no exact amount)</li>
<li>Some mayo (again, not exact)</li>
<li>Salt, pepper, spices</li>
</ul>


<p>Take the next 20-30 minutes to prepare, thusly:</p>

<ol>
<li>Cook pasta. This will take about 20 minutes between bringing the water to a boil and the 12-14 minute cooking time. Which is great, because while it&#8217;s cooking, you&#8230;</li>
<li>Dice the onion and celery. Finely diced is best, but this is an inexact science type of dish, so don&#8217;t sweat it.</li>
<li>When ready, drain the pasta, let it cool a bit (don&#8217;t rinse it, just let it cool in your strainer)</li>
<li>Empty the pasta in a big mixing/salad bowl and add salt and pepper to taste. I also sometimes add oregano or light garlic spices, so play with it a bit. Don&#8217;t over-do it, because next you&#8217;ll&#8230;</li>
<li>Add the diced onions and celery.</li>
<li>Open the cans of shrimp, drain the water from them, and add the shrimp to the bowl and mix everything together with a spatula or wooden spoon.</li>
<li>Add mayo. Add it in rounds, you&#8217;d like your component parts to all have some mayo on them, but by no means be covered in the stuff.</li>
<li>Cover the bowl. Chill for a few hours in the fridge.</li>
<li>Remove from the fridge when cold, give it another few stirs and dish it out.</li>
</ol>


<p>You can try this with any type of pasta, but the shells are the best, because they occasionally create these shrimp-onion-celery-pasta bombs in one single bite when they catch everything together. It&#8217;s grand.</p>

<p>This makes me think of my Mom. It makes me think of summer. It makes me happy. It&#8217;s a perfect compliment to burgers, hot dogs, and anything else you&#8217;re whipping up on the grill.</p>

<p>Enjoy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shutting the Door, For Now]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/05/18/shutting-the-door-for-now/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/05/18/shutting-the-door-for-now</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I captured all of the contents of articles that were submitted to my favorite website from ten years ago and tucked them behind a locked door. I am, of course, speaking of <strong><a href="http://thosekids.org/fatdog/">fatDOG</a></strong>, the personal website of mine that exploded into an online journal featuring more than 30 authors when I took my first public foray into data-backed website development.</p>

<p>One could almost draw a straight line from the technical things I was playing with at that time (late 2000 to early 2001, for those not keeping track) to the career in which I now call myself a professional.</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://thosekids.org/fatdog/">fatDOG</a></strong> was so much more than that, though. I learned over the years that it was an arena for many of my friends &#8212; and even their friends &#8212; to express themselves in ways they could not afford to anywhere else. Some played with poetry to various degrees of success, others cranked out opinion pieces, and some put together serial stories that remain some of the best writing I&#8217;ve read.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The ways in which this simple website &#8212; a multi-author blog before such a thing was commonplace or simple to do &#8212; touched people are numerous. It touched the authors in a special way, and they were then able to reach out to the readers, sparking conversation about topics as far ranging as love, life, drugs, careers, music, fear, self-doubt, and confidence.</p>

<p>This website captured the emotions of a few dozen people in their late teens and early twenties as they experienced high school graduation, entering college, the September 11th attacks, and the personal battles of college and quarter-life. To this day, it is shocking and fun to read it all back.</p>

<p>So, while I have made the decision to &#8220;lock the door&#8221; on the website as a new annual bill of hosting quickly approaches, I have not and will not lose the key. I will be bringing all of nearly 600 original articles submitted to the website back online in the near future, and asking my contributors to come back for a bit and comment on their thoughts, fears, and work from up to ten years ago.</p>

<p>I can&#8217;t wait to find out what we all think of ourselves when the time comes to look back at the places from which we all came.</p>

<p>To the many authors and readers, friends and lurkers &#8212; you remain the integral part of the favorite thing I have ever built. I encourage you to head over to <strong><a href="http://thosekids.org/fatdog/">fatDOG</a></strong>, now, and review some choice quotes and many of the site&#8217;s famous splash images in the special &#8220;locked&#8221; page that is now up.</p>

<p>Love,</p>

<p>Colin</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>Bask in the history of the fatDOG website at <a href="http://thosekids.org/fatdog/">http://thosekids.org/fatdog/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Married!]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/04/03/married/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/04/03/married</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Liz and I have tied the knot! April 2, 2011 was the best day of my life! I was surrounded by family and close friends for the greatest celebrations of love.</p>

<p>You are the love of my life, Liz!</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Things Spambots Blast]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/01/06/the-things-spambots-blast/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/01/06/the-things-spambots-blast</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I don&#8217;t get much in the way of traffic on my blog&#8217;s comments, but always have good &#8216;ol Akismet kicking up lots of spam for me. Normally, it&#8217;s your usual, run-of-the-mill, easily-identifiable sex references, but occasionally it&#8217;s kind of mean. Case in point:</p>

<blockquote><p>I used to love reading your blog, but lately it’s been a little boring. I’ll still read it though =)</p></blockquote>

<p>That&#8217;s harsh, spam robot! I&#8217;ve just started up blogging again and here you go knocking down my self-esteem. I suppose my blog <em>was</em> more original and interesting for the months upon months that I left it dormant. Now that I&#8217;m wasting your time spewing my thoughts into it, it&#8217;s a little hard to take, right? Sorry &#8217;bout that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Way to Fix the NFL Playoffs]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/01/03/a-way-to-fix-the-nfl-playoffs/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/01/03/a-way-to-fix-the-nfl-playoffs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://mccolin.github.io/images/asset/nfl-logo-footer-2010.png" title="NFL Logo" ></p>

<p>There&rsquo;s a lot of talk&hellip; err&hellip; complaining about the NFL Playoffs. This is mostly because there are a lot of teams with better records than their first-round opponents that will be at a home field <em>dis</em>advantage in the first round, and mostly because there&rsquo;s one team &#8212; the Seattle Seahawks &#8212; who will be hosting a playoff game after a season with a losing record of 7-9.</p>

<p>So here goes.. let&rsquo;s fix this! But fear not &mdash; we won&rsquo;t get too drastic.</p>

<h2>Let&rsquo;s get started in the NFC</h2>

<p>To get us started, let&rsquo;s go over the NFC final standings and playoff seatings, according to current NFL rules:</p>

<ol>
<li>Atlanta Falcons (13-3, winners of NFC South)</li>
<li>Chicago Bears (11-5, winners of NFC North)</li>
<li>Philadelphia Eagles (10-6, winners of NFC East)</li>
<li>Seattle Seahawks (7-9, winners of NFC West)</li>
<li>New Orleans Saints (11-5, wildcard from NFC South)</li>
<li>Green Bay Packers (10-6, wildcard from NFC North)</li>
</ol>


<p>Now, it&rsquo;s worth mentioning that two teams finished with records better than the Seahawks, but did not qualify for the playoffs by virtue of not winning their division. Those unfortunate teams are:</p>

<ul>
<li>New York Giants (10-6, 2nd place in NFC East due to 0-2 record against Eagles)</li>
<li>Tampa Bay Buccaneers (10-6, 3rd place in NFC South behind the Saints and Falcons)</li>
</ul>


<p>Now, it&rsquo;s unfortunate that a 7-9 Seahawks team gets in ahead of those teams, but there&rsquo;s no way a team that wins their division shouldn&rsquo;t get into the playoffs. So, yes, the Seahawks play in a crappy division and the Giants and Bucs play in considerably difficult divisions, but that&rsquo;s the way it goes. You win your division, you get in. And you should.</p>

<p>The problem is that those very same 7-9 Seahawks are actually going to host the far-better-performing 11-5 Saints in the Wildcard weekend, when &#8212; had the Saints been in any other division, they&rsquo;d be waiting at home with a first round bye this coming weekend. That&rsquo;s a tough break for the Saints.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the thing &mdash; if you want a bye, you should have to win your division. Plain and simple. There has to be a prize for winning your division and there has to be a punishment for failing to do so.</p>

<p>BUT, in the Wildcard weekend, all (okay, most) bets should be off. The Saints should be hosting a game, just by virtue of having the best record among the four teams playing in Wildcard weekend.</p>

<p>So here&rsquo;s my plan for re-doing the playoff seating:</p>

<ol>
<li>The four <strong>division winners are in the playoffs</strong>. Your prize for winning a division, even if you do it as crappily as the Seahawks, is that you get to play in the playoffs. This is the same as currently.</li>
<li>The <strong>next best two teams also get in the playoffs</strong>. They didn&rsquo;t win their divisions, but they&rsquo;re freaking good enough to play for a championship. This is also the same as currently.</li>
<li>The <strong>best two division winners have first-round byes</strong>. Settle this with the usual tie-breakers. This would actually keep this year&rsquo;s NFC picture the same as it is, now. Atlanta and Chicago would stay warm and healthy by the fire for the first week of the playoffs. This rule is the same as present. No major changes, yet.</li>
<li>To decide the order of the <strong>wildcard teams, go by best record</strong>, don&rsquo;t initially take division crowns into consideration. This would change the order of the wildcard teams to New Orleans, Green Bay, Philadelphia, Seattle. That&rsquo;s almost a flip-flop. The games would be the same, but the home teams would change.</li>
<li>But! If there is a tie in determining the wildcard seating, <strong>use division championship as the first tie-breaker</strong>. This would mean that though Green Bay and Philadelphia have the same record, and Green Bay has the head-to-head advantage over the Eagles, the Eagles would be seated ahead of the Packers by virtue of winning their division.</li>
</ol>


<p>Now, under these rules, we&rsquo;d see a fairly close seating to what we have, now, but there wouldn&rsquo;t be gross favoritism for division-winning wildcards, only moderate favoritism. If you think about it, a 10-6 Eagles team that was beat in week 1 by a 10-6 Packers team, but was able to win their division when the Packers couldn&rsquo;t, should get home field in that matchup. However, a 7-9 Seahawks team should just be happy <em>to be in the playoffs</em>, and they haven&rsquo;t <em>earned</em> a home playoff game over an 11-5 Saints team that had to battle through a division that could&rsquo;ve easily produced three playoff teams.</p>

<p>So, NFL Competition Committee, I hope you&rsquo;re listening. Here&rsquo;s how the NFC Playoff Standings would shake-down under these new, adjusted rules:</p>

<ol>
<li>Atlanta Falcons (13-3, NFC South Champs, Best Conference Record)</li>
<li>Chicago Bears (11-5, NFC North Champs, First Round Bye)</li>
<li>New Orleans Saints (11-5, 2nd Place NFC South, Best Wildcard Round Record, Home Team for Wildcard Round)</li>
<li>Philadelphia Eagles (10-6, NFC East Champs, Home Team for Wildcard Round)</li>
<li>Green Bay Packers (10-6, 2nd Place NFC North, Visit Philadelphia in Wildcard Round)</li>
<li>Seattle Seahawks (7-9, NFC West Champs, Visit New Orleans in Wildcard Round)</li>
</ol>


<p>That&rsquo;s a lot more stomach-able, yes!? It just makes sense. We shouldn&rsquo;t toss the Seahawks out altogether, because winning your division counts for <em>something</em>, but at 7-9, shouldn&rsquo;t they just be happy to be in the tournament? And under this, the best team in the wildcard round gets a home game. You&rsquo;re welcome, New Orleans Saints.</p>

<h2>How does that shake out in the AFC?</h2>

<p>If you&rsquo;re curious, here&rsquo;s how this would impact the AFC. The AFC breaks down like this under current NFL rules:</p>

<ol>
<li>New England Patriots (14-2, AFC East Champs, Best Overall Record)</li>
<li>Pittsburgh Steelers (12-4, AFC North Champs, First Round Bye)</li>
<li>Indianapolis Colts (10-6, AFC South Champs, Home Wildcard Game)</li>
<li>Kansas City Chiefs (10-6, AFC West Champs, Home Wildcard Game)</li>
<li>Baltimore Ravens (12-4, 2nd Place AFC North, Road Wildcard Game)</li>
<li>NY Jets (11-5, 2nd Place AFC East, Road Wildcard Game)</li>
</ol>


<p>Let&rsquo;s ignore the preposterous fact that the Colts of Indianapolis are somehow in the AFC South division for a second and analyze how the seetings shake out. The Colts and Chiefs <em>both</em> have worse records than the teams they&rsquo;ll <em>host</em> in the wildcard round. Both of them! The Pats and Steelers took care of business, sure, but the Ravens and Jets are getting screwed, here. Under our new seating rules, you&rsquo;d get this:</p>

<ol>
<li>New England Patriots (14-2, AFC East Champs, Home Field Advantage)</li>
<li>Pittsburgh Steelers (12-4, AFC North Champs, First Round Bye)</li>
<li>Baltimore Ravens (12-4, 2nd Place AFC North, Home Wildcard Game)</li>
<li>NY Jets (11-5, 2nd Place AFC East, Home Wildcard Game)</li>
<li>Indianapolis Colts (10-6, AFC South Champs but bad record, Visit New York in Wildcard Round)</li>
<li>Kansas City Chiefs (10-6, AFC West Champs but bad record, Lost tie-breaker to Colts, Visit Baltimore in Wildcard Round)</li>
</ol>


<p>And that is how it should line up. The getting into the playoffs is not the problem. It&rsquo;s the way we&rsquo;re lining up the teams once they&rsquo;re there. A steller Ravens team should not have to go on the road to visit a barely-better-than-mediocre Chiefs team, but the Chiefs belong in the playoffs as the best team in their division, however weak a division it is- and it was pretty weak, this year. When will San Diego put together a full season!?</p>

<p>Likewise, the Seattle Seahawks won their division. It will take a team of NASA scientists and MIT mathematicians to figure out how they won a division with a losing record, but they did do it, so they belong in the tournament. They don&rsquo;t, however, deserve to host the far superior (four wins superior, in fact) New Orleans team in a playoff game.</p>

<p>What say you, NFL Competition Overlords- I mean, Committee!?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movies I Saw From 2010]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/01/02/movies-i-saw-from-2010/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/01/02/movies-i-saw-from-2010</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was not a particularly great movie-going year for me. I just realized that I haven&#8217;t seen a single movie in the thick of the Oscar discussion for the overall picture, director, and actor/actress awards. I&#8217;ve leant strongly toward comedies, which makes this seem a bit of a more base list than I&#8217;d like, but it&#8217;s still worth a recap.</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s a look at all of the movies <em>first released</em> in 2010 that I happened to see &#8212; either in theater or otherwise &#8212; with a rundown of my thoughts. Movies are listed in order by release date.</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leap_Year_(2010_film)"><img class="alignleft" title="Leap Year Poster" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/d/da/Leap_year_poster.jpg" alt="Leap Year Poster" width="125" /></a><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leap_Year_(2010_film)">Leap Year</a></strong><br/>
<em>with Amy Adams, Matthew Goode, and Adam Scott (a personal favorite of mine)</em><br/>
<em>Released to Theaters January 6. Seen on HBO in November.</em><br/>
In most ways, Leap Year, is an utterly predictable and fairly uninteresting romantic/road-trip comedy. Amy Adams is always wonderful to look at and plays the two traits of her role, well. Matthew Goode, who I know very little about, is perfectly great as the Irishman that wins her heart. It&#8217;s upsetting to see Adam Scott playing such a tool, here, but he&#8217;s good at it, and there&#8217;s the quick inclusion of Always Sunny&#8217;s Kaitlin Olsen. Anything that has any amount of Sweet Dee earns a few notches.</p>

<p>This was cutesy and well worth catching on cable. For its positives and generally vanilla lack of negatives, I give it <strong>3 shamrocks of out 5</strong>.</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/8/8a/Crazies_ver2.jpg"><img class="alignleft" title="The Crazies Poster" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/8/8a/Crazies_ver2.jpg" alt="The Crazies Poster" width="125" /></a><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Crazies_(2010_film)">The Crazies</a></strong><br/>
<em>with Timothy Olyphant and Radha Mitchell<br/>
Released to Theaters February 26. Rented from Blockbuster (and subsequently returned late, which they still call me about) in August.</em><br/>
This being a George A. Romero production and a remake of a Romero classic, I had much much much (is that enough muches, yet?) higher hopes for this zombie-like-but-not-quite-zombie movie. There&#8217;s a contamination in the water source turning people in a podunk town all sorts of&#8230; get this&#8230; crazy. And who&#8217;s going to deal with them? The Sheriff, of course. If I&#8217;m being honest, this is a perfectly passable horror movie, with a handful of great scenes and sequences. Plus, there&#8217;s the whole &#8220;figure out if a member of our group is infected&#8221; thing, which is always a mind-bender&#8230; but this ain&#8217;t even a good zombie movie, let alone good movie.</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s to hoping they try harder on the next remake of Romero classic. I give The Crazies <strong>2 out of 5 military containment officers</strong>.</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hot_Tub_Time_Machine"><img class="alignleft" title="Hot Tub Time Machine Poster" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/6/64/Hot_tub_time_machine_poster.jpg" alt="Hot Tub Time Machine Poster" width="125" /></a><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hot_Tub_Time_Machine">Hot Tub Time Machine</a></strong><br/>
<em>with John Cusack, Rob Corddry, Clark Duke, and Craig Robinson. Plus Chevy Chase!<br/>
Released to Theaters March 26. Seen in theater on March 26. And again on HBO recently. </em><br/>
Having now seen this &#8220;film&#8221; for a second time, I can be more objective, but I&#8217;ll start by saying this movie gave moviegoers what it advertised: lots of 80&#8242;s references (both direct and sneaky), lots of stupid 80&#8242;s jokes, and lots of crude, juvenile humor. And you know what? It&#8217;s freaking fun to watch. It&#8217;s not a great time-travel movie. It&#8217;s not a great 80&#8242;s movie, which I suppose it only sort-of is in the first place. On the surface, it makes you feel like John Cusack grabbed some friends to go to the well for some cash, but there&#8217;s enough percolating in here (like everything involving Crispin Glover, the ski patrol kids mistaking the guys for Russian spies, or the many 80&#8242;s movie homages) that make you think it&#8217;s a real effort. And it&#8217;s pretty funny. If you bring your most critical eye, you&#8217;ll find every flaw, but if you sit back and enjoy the ride, you&#8217;ll be cracking up all the way through Rob Corddry&#8217;s Motlue Crue video in the end credits.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s worth a spin. I give it <strong>4 russian energy drinks out of a possible 5</strong>.</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toy_Story_3"><img class="alignleft" title="Toy Story 3 Poster" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/0/0e/Toy_story3_poster3-1-.jpg" alt="Toy Story 3 Poster" width="125" /></a><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toy_Story_3">Toy Story 3</a></strong><br/>
<em>with the voice talents of Tom Hanks, Tim Allen, and many more including Kristen Schaal!<br/>
Released to the world June 18. <a href="http://lizandcolin.tumblr.com/post/752021107/line-at-movies-in-bakersfield-for-twilight-we">Seen in Bakersfield, CA while moving across the country on June 29</a>.</em><br/>
The verdict on this one seems like it&#8217;s been settled since before or perhaps immediately after it&#8217;s release. Every critic and every fan seems to think this is Pixar&#8217;s finest movie and possibly one of the finest animated feature films ever. While I don&#8217;t disagree that it&#8217;s a great movie, this is not the best animated film ever made. It&#8217;s probably not the best Pixar movie and it may not even be the best Toy Story movie. BUT, all of that said, this is a great movie that &#8212; in true Pixar fashion &#8212; has layers that work for the kids, layers that work for the parents, and layers that work for people like me that are neither of the before stated categories. Seeing this in Bakersfield for something like $6 a ticket was a sweet plus, too! There&#8217;s not much to say that hasn&#8217;t been said, and I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;re familiar with this Toy Story business, already. If you&#8217;ve seen 1 and 2, go see this one. If you haven&#8217;t seen the prequels, check those out and make it a point to see this quite great final chapter.</p>

<p>Give it a look as soon as you find yourself in the mood. <strong>4 and &frac12; potato heads out of 5</strong>.</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knight_and_Day"><img class="alignleft" title="Knight and Day" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/5/51/Knight_and_day_09.jpg" alt="Knight and Day Poster" width="125" height="185" /></a><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knight_and_Day">Knight and Day</a></strong><br/>
<em>with Tom Cruise and Cameron Diaz<br/>
Released to theaters June 23. Seen in theater in Flagstaff, AZ on July 1.</em><br/>
This movie apparently did not do well in US box office, but recouped expenses and much more internationally. It&#8217;s a shame it didn&#8217;t get seen by more people, because this movie was freaking great. This movie broke my long-lasting dislike of Tom Cruise, though my disdain was crumbling a bit after Tropic Thunder. The stunts, the sights, the love story, the action elements, and generally everything except the old man chewing popcorn loudly near me were great about this movie. I don&#8217;t even typically like Cameron Diaz, but this movie was really fun and exciting. It&#8217;s well-written, well-acted, and has a few great twists to keep you going. If a certain Scott Pilgrim hadn&#8217;t hit theaters later in the summer, this would have easily been the &#8220;funnest&#8221; movie I saw in 2010.</p>

<p>I highly recommend it, regardless of your feelings for or against Tom Cruise. I give it <strong>5 out of 5 motorcycle chases</strong>. Seriously.</p>

<p>I might as well get this out of the way. Despite my best intentions, I did miss the following summer biggies, which I&#8217;d fully hoped to see, during the busy July stretch. I hope to catch them, soon:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Despicable_Me">Despicable Me</a>, July 9. <em>It funny I didn&#8217;t see this, considering how much I quoted it throughout Liz&#8217; and my cross-country trip.</em></li>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Kids_Are_All_Right_(film)">The Kids Are All Right</a>, July 9. <em>I have a soft spot for Mark Ruffalo, but I&#8217;m not sure why.</em></li>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inception_(film)">Inception</a>, July 16. <em>I swear I&#8217;ll see it soon. Nerds, stop chastising me for not having seen it, yet. And stop going on about the new Tron. I won&#8217;t ever see that.</em></li>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dinner_for_Schmucks">Dinner for Schmucks</a>, July 30. <em>It feels like this came out over a year ago with the way it came and went, but it has Steve Carrel, Paul Rudd, AND Jemaine Clement. That&#8217;s a trifecta for me.</em></li>
</ul>


<p><span style="line-height: 24px;">Back to the next (and last) movie from 2010 that I actually did see:</span></p>

<p><span style="line-height: 24px;"><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scott_Pilgrim_vs._the_World"><img class="alignleft" title="Scott Pilgrim vs the World Poster" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/1/14/Scott_Pilgrim_vs._the_World_teaser.jpg" alt="Scott Pilgrim vs the World Poster" width="125" /></a><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scott_Pilgrim_vs._the_World">Scott Pilgrim vs. the World</a></strong><br /> <em>with Michael Cera, Mary Elizabeth Winstead, Jason Schwartzman. Kieran Culkin steals many a scene, as well.<br /> Released in theaters August 13. Seen in theaters on August 13. Then again a week later.</em><br /> In know &#8212; Michael Cera&#8217;s probably worn out his welcome in your household, too. I mean, he&#8217;s always playing the same character and it&#8217;s rarely as likable as good &#8216;ol George Michael Bluth, am I right!? Not so, it turns out. This movie, done by the impeccable Edgar Wright of <em>Hot Fuzz</em> and <em>Shawn of the Dead</em> fame, is a re-imagining of a comic book series that actually draws direct inspiration from the panels on the comic pages. They did cram six full graphic novels into one movie, which leaves some plot lines unfinished and makes you feel it&#8217;s a big frayed around some edges, but the visuals, spot-on reproductions of the comic book characters, and killer soundtrack more than make up for it. Even if Michael Cera is making you queasy these days, you can look past some of his weird mannerisms and concentrate on the hilarious, witty, and fun interpretation of the absurd situations Scott Pilgrim gets into.</span></p>

<p><span style="line-height: 24px;">This movie didn&#8217;t get even make back its budget at the box office, which is a freakin&#8217; shame. Grab the DVD or catch this on Netflix ASAP. I give it a full <strong>5 out of 5 shipments from Amazon.ca</strong>. What&#8217;s the website for that, again?</span></p>

<p>&#8211;</p>

<p>Awesome. The funniest thing about this year may be that I didn&#8217;t see another movie after Scott Pilgrim. I&#8217;ve been cruising through the list and can&#8217;t find another one I did see. There were ones I&#8217;d hoped to see, but I suppose I just didn&#8217;t set my watch to walk up and pay $10 for the &#8220;privilege&#8221; of trying them out.</p>

<p>In September, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Town_(2010_film)">The Town</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Easy_A">Easy A</a> both happened, which I intended to see. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Let_Me_In_(film)">Let Me In</a>, a fun-looking Americanization of <em>Let the Right One In</em>, dropped in October, along with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Social_Network">The Social Network</a>, which is getting all sorts of praise. I missed them all. While I&#8217;m at it, I&#8217;ll point out that I also wanted to see <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nowhere_Boy">Nowhere Boy</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_(2010_film)">Red</a>, but couldn&#8217;t tell when they were coming out form their trailers. Into November, I missed <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harry_Potter_and_the_Deathly_Hallows_(film)">Harry Potter 7</a>, which is pretty radical for someone who has seen all Harry Potter movies within a week of their opening. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Love_and_Other_Drugs">Love and Other Drugs</a> looked good, but got lost in the holiday season along with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Swan_(film)">Black Swan</a> and that new Disney farce. I will soon enough see <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Fighter_(2010_film)">The Fighter</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/True_Grit_(2010_film)">True Grit</a>, which came out in December, though probably not in that order. They both look spectacular.</p>

<p>So there you have it! A look back at a lackluster year of moviegoing from your&#8217;s truly.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Engagement Photos]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/12/22/engagement-photos/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/12/22/engagement-photos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Liz and I have, like, the best photographer, ever! We met her at University of Delaware for our engagement photo shoot (11 months after getting engaged! Who says we&#8217;re behind the ball!?) and she made us look seriously beautiful. Well, she didn&#8217;t have to try too hard to make Liz look stunning, but she did manage to make me look fabulous, as well.</p>

<p>Our photographer <a href="http://photosbylaurie.wordpress.com/2010/11/21/colin-liz-engagement-shoot/">featured some of the photos from the session on her blog. Check it out</a>.</p>

<p><img src="http://mccolin.github.io/images/asset/229-300x199.jpg" title="&#34;Colin and Liz Engagement Photo and University of Delaware&#34;" alt="&#34;Colin and Liz Engagement Photo and University of Delaware&#34;"></p>

<p>Makes me look forward to working more with Laurie at <a href="http://www.lizandcolin.us/">our wedding</a>. Which is coming up in just over three months. Whew!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pummelvision Made Me Smile]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/12/19/pummelvision-made-me-smile/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/12/19/pummelvision-made-me-smile</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This thing is really fun and useful. I made a Pummelvision based on my Flickr photos, which are admittedly not up-to-date (large chunk missing in the middle), but this was still spectacular to watch. Probably moreso for me than you, but still.</p>

<p>Make your own at <a href="http://pummelvision.com/">pummelvision</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Train rides are interesting]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/12/17/train-rides-are-interesting/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/12/17/train-rides-are-interesting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Too many people. Loud ticket checkers. Not as fast moving as you&#8217;d think. Kids from college crammed in on their way home for the semester break. Fairly meh seats. High fares.</p>

<p>Next time Bolt bus?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cliff Lee makes me happy.]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/12/16/cliff-lee-makes-me-happy/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/12/16/cliff-lee-makes-me-happy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cliff Lee makes me happy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Living with Birds]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/09/20/on-living-with-birds/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/09/20/on-living-with-birds</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="  alignright" title="Me and Pepper" src="http://colinmccloskey.com/things/colin_and_pepper.jpg" alt="Me and Pepper" width="250" /></p>

<p>Or bird, rather. This is Pepper, Liz&#8217; Mom&#8217;s bird. Pepper is very pretty (she even acknowledges this by saying &#8220;Pretty Birdy&#8221; often) and is kind of cute. And then you get near her and she becomes quite the pest.</p>

<p>You see, Pepper is pretty spoiled. She gets to do what she wants and most of the time she gets to do it when she wants. When her Mommy went out of town, however, on a recent vacation, most of the bird-sitting duties fell to&#8230; me&#8230; the stranger with the beard.</p>

<p>She didn&#8217;t take to me right away. Oh sure, I&#8217;d occasionally bring her over to the garbage can so she could poop away from her cage. And I&#8217;d occasionally make some sounds that she could respond to. But sometimes I&#8217;d forget to leave her music on. Or I&#8217;d not get downstairs early enough in the morning to let her out. Or I&#8217;d yell at her for squawking so loudly in my ear. It wasn&#8217;t her ideal arrangement. After all, where was her Mommy? Who is this guy?</p>

<p>But a funny thing happened halfway through her second day being stuck with me. She started to like me. She started to like me so much, in fact, that she wouldn&#8217;t leave me alone. She demanded that I let her sit on my shoulder. She chirped and cooed at me and rubbed her beak on me playfully. She cried when I left the room. She wouldn&#8217;t let me take her off of my shoulder. She was generally sick without me nearby.</p>

<p>And I finally understood. If you&#8217;re nice (enough) to the bird, she&#8217;ll come to accept you. And while I was nowhere near as cool as her Mommy, I was better than nobody. A lot better than nobody. So she clutched to me fiercely.</p>

<p>It all worked itself out. A vacation in Miami can last only so long and when it was over, Pepper&#8217;s Mommy returned. She has since calmed down considerably. Oh sure, I&#8217;m not really important to her, anymore, because her mom&#8217;s back, and I&#8217;m more comfortable *not* having a bird all over me half the time&#8230; but we&#8217;ll always have those four or so days.</p>

<p>We&#8217;ll always have that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Helped on a Phanatic Journey]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/09/14/i-helped-on-a-phanatic-journey/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/09/14/i-helped-on-a-phanatic-journey</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My friends Jess and Dana have been embarking on a journey to photograph themselves with every statue of the Phillie Phanatic that has been across Philadelphia in the recent &#8220;Phanatic About Town&#8221; promotion. Local artists put their own spin on the Phanatic by building themed statues of him. The statues were placed in different locations in the city, and are actually now up for auction.</p>

<p>Jess and Dana wanted a photo of themselves with every Phanatic statue. And, as luck would have it, the Phillies held an event at Citizens Bank Park this past weekend where you could get next to every one of the statues. It&#8217;s kind of cheating, but it works. I helped them take the pictures at the park! And I had a hot dog! It was great!</p>

<div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 310px">
  <a href="http://danajessicaphanatic.tumblr.com/"><img class=" " title="Dana Jess Phanatic" src="http://s3.amazonaws.com/data.tumblr.com/tumblr_l4l843K49d1qcwf9zo1_1280.jpg?AWSAccessKeyId=0RYTHV9YYQ4W5Q3HQMG2&Expires=1284586960&Signature=9BaoTG5PuGZ8Z4iKcPL1zxEY4Pw%3D" alt="Dana and Jess and Phanatic" width="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">
    Dana and Jess in one of their original Phanatic photos
  </p>
</div>


<p><a href="http://danajessicaphanatic.tumblr.com/"><img class="  alignnone" title="Phanatic Franklin" src="http://colinmccloskey.com/things/PhanaticFranklin.jpg" alt="Phanatic Franklin" width="400" height="532" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[56kbps MP3s are the Worst]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/05/15/56kbps-mp3s-are-the-worst/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/05/15/56kbps-mp3s-are-the-worst</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>About ten years ago, probably, it would be a semi-frequent pastime of me and some of my geekier friends to get together in one another&#8217;s basements, connect our computers via a series of wires, gadgets, and switches. You see, wireless networks were not prevalent (or inexpensive) at the time, so it would take about an hour or more to get all set up. Once we finally got it altogether, we&#8217;d play a few first person shooter games, sports games, etc., drink lots of soda, and generally geek out until morning.</p>

<p>Some of the games were not of my most interest, however. Back at home, my parents did not have fast Internet (like that of many of my friends), so what I would spend a big portion of my time doing, is searching through my friends&#8217; computers for MP3&#8242;s, videos, and other interesting files, copying them over to my machine if I found them particularly interesting.</p>

<p>My friend Drew had a large collection of MP3&#8242;s that were of interest to me: Nirvana&#8217;s entire catalog, various Incubus archives, other bands I enjoyed. So, without thinking twice, I copied everything he had that was interesting onto my own computer.</p>

<p>Thing is &#8212; these MP3&#8242;s of Drews are of a particularly low quality. MP3&#8242;s have a bit-rate, which essentially is a measure of how much information is contained in each second of music within the file. Naturally, the higher the bit-rate, the more information in the song, the larger the MP3 file. Keep in mind that this was circa 1999-2001, when hard disks didn&#8217;t come nearly as large as they do now, and didn&#8217;t come nearly as cheaply as they do, now, either.</p>

<p>CD-quality is essentially 128kbps (meaning 128 kilobits of information are contained in each second of music). Drew &#8212; who perhaps doesn&#8217;t possess &#8220;audiophile&#8221; level hearing &#8212; had made a decision to store all of his MP3s at 56kbps to save space (on his small, expensive hard drive). He saved space and the expense of reduced quality, which he couldn&#8217;t tell the difference. And to be fair, I couldn&#8217;t tell the difference too much, either.</p>

<p>But then speakers got better. And iPods came out. And headphones got better. And and and and&#8230; 56kbps MP3s that previously sounded adequate started to sound like absolute crap. Drums are tinny, vocals are scratchy, and the details are missing. They don&#8217;t take up much space, though.</p>

<p>So here it is 2010. Disk space is large and disk space is cheap. Speakers and headphones are of high quality. And I still have about 80 really, really low quality MP3s hanging around that have followed me from computer-to-computer-to-computer over the years.</p>

<p>These low-quality files come up occasionally when I&#8217;m on shuffle and at first I won&#8217;t notice. I&#8217;ll get into it. Then when that chorus hits and Dave Grohl&#8217;s drumming starts to sound like Doug Funnie banging on a trash can, I know.</p>

<p>Drew, your MP3 from ten years ago got me again!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Carded]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/04/29/carded/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/04/29/carded</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Getting a new business card has always been exciting to me. It&rsquo;s just a small piece of paper that I don&rsquo;t frequently give out, but it just feels great to have it in hand. It&rsquo;s like a validation.</p>

<p>Could&rsquo;ve used this before f8, but oh well.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Miss&#8230;]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/04/01/i-miss/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/04/01/i-miss</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some things that pop into mind that I think fondly of, but don&#8217;t currently have&#8230;</p>

<p><strong>I miss driving</strong>. Listening to music possibly too loud while on the way to work. Keeping up with the radio. Just generally controlling my own pace and being able to go beyond the city in which I live. I don&#8217;t miss having to find parking, though.</p>

<p><strong>I miss thunderstorms.</strong> It rains here, but it&#8217;s that weird, unfulfilling, cold rain. Everyone uses umbrellas they don&#8217;t need and nearly poke out my eye as we pass on the sidewalk. And thunderstorms are just cool. I love watching it pour rain outside from under a porch roof in the summer. The smell. Lots of things.</p>

<p><strong>I miss hoagies</strong>. You just can&#8217;t get the same thing here. And I want one. Often.</p>

<p>Sigh.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[String Cheese Strategy: Pocket Warmer]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/03/29/string-cheese-strategy-pocket-warmer/"/>
    <updated>2010-03-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/03/29/string-cheese-strategy-pocket-warmer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When eating string cheese, I find that I&#8217;m typically looking for a different flavor experience than when I&#8217;m eating regular-old-mozzarella. Not only is string cheese a &#8220;fun&#8221; cheese that I expect to shred apart with my hands, it&#8217;s a different thing altogether.</p>

<p>What I&#8217;m getting at is&#8230; I like my string cheese warm. Not cold like I prefer balls or slices of mozzarella.</p>

<p>How do I get it warm? I&#8217;m glad you asked. My favorite snack-strategy developed at my new job is the string cheese pocket warm-up. It&#8217;s pretty simple:</p>

<ol>
<li>Grab a string cheese from the fridge</li>
<li>Put it in your pocket (keep it wrapped, please!)</li>
<li>Walk around and talk to a few people.</li>
<li>Get back to work</li>
<li>Then&#8230; remember you have the string cheese in your pocket.</li>
<li>Promptly remove and devour.</li>
</ol>


<p>Wonderful.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
