<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Topic: Travel | This is Colin McCloskey]]></title>
  <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-06T13:39:49-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://mccolin.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Colin McCloskey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pummelvision Made Me Smile]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/12/19/pummelvision-made-me-smile/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/12/19/pummelvision-made-me-smile</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This thing is really fun and useful. I made a Pummelvision based on my Flickr photos, which are admittedly not up-to-date (large chunk missing in the middle), but this was still spectacular to watch. Probably moreso for me than you, but still.</p>

<p>Make your own at <a href="http://pummelvision.com/">pummelvision</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Train rides are interesting]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/12/17/train-rides-are-interesting/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/12/17/train-rides-are-interesting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Too many people. Loud ticket checkers. Not as fast moving as you&#8217;d think. Kids from college crammed in on their way home for the semester break. Fairly meh seats. High fares.</p>

<p>Next time Bolt bus?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stuck in Rock City]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2009/06/30/stuck-in-rock-city/"/>
    <updated>2009-06-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2009/06/30/stuck-in-rock-city</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Liz and I are on our way home for a vacation and visit with family. We haven&#8217;t had a length of time back east since Christmas, so we&#8217;ve been looking forward to this for quite some time. It&#8217;d be a lie to say were haven&#8217;t been counting down the days for the past two weeks or so.</p>

<p>So you can imagine we were excited to finally be in the air and on our way this morning. We caught a cab at the crack of dawn (or just before ~5:30) this morning and were waiting for takeoff by five after seven. Certainly an early start for both of us. Well, to be accurate a late night for me, since I hadn&#8217;t (and still as of yet have not) slept. I got a new computer and was otherwise wired, so after packing I played on the computer until the wee hours of cab-time.</p>

<p>The flight was terrible. And that&#8217;s even before I consider that the flight didn&#8217;t even take us where we were supposed to go! I&#8217;m typing this entry from a terminal in a Detroit waiting to figure out when we&#8217;ll be back on our way to New Jersey. Sure, there&#8217;s some prickly weather out there, but it&#8217;s sunny here as I type this.</p>

<p>This is my first time in Detroit. I must say, Gate B5 is a charming site. And the moving walkway to my right is pretty exciting. All-in-all, there&#8217;s a lot to see in Detroit even within the fifty foot radius I&#8217;m allowed to stay while I wait for boarding updates.</p>

<p>Sigh.</p>

<p>Rumor has it they&#8217;re getting things together for us. Maybe we *will* eventually get home, after all!</p>

<p>Until next time, Detroit!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
