<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Topic: SanFran | This is Colin McCloskey]]></title>
  <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/categories/sanfran/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-28T20:04:58-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://mccolin.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Colin McCloskey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pummelvision Made Me Smile]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/12/19/pummelvision-made-me-smile/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/12/19/pummelvision-made-me-smile</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This thing is really fun and useful. I made a Pummelvision based on my Flickr photos, which are admittedly not up-to-date (large chunk missing in the middle), but this was still spectacular to watch. Probably moreso for me than you, but still.</p>

<p>Make your own at <a href="http://pummelvision.com/">pummelvision</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Miss&#8230;]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/04/01/i-miss/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/04/01/i-miss</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some things that pop into mind that I think fondly of, but don&#8217;t currently have&#8230;</p>

<p><strong>I miss driving</strong>. Listening to music possibly too loud while on the way to work. Keeping up with the radio. Just generally controlling my own pace and being able to go beyond the city in which I live. I don&#8217;t miss having to find parking, though.</p>

<p><strong>I miss thunderstorms.</strong> It rains here, but it&#8217;s that weird, unfulfilling, cold rain. Everyone uses umbrellas they don&#8217;t need and nearly poke out my eye as we pass on the sidewalk. And thunderstorms are just cool. I love watching it pour rain outside from under a porch roof in the summer. The smell. Lots of things.</p>

<p><strong>I miss hoagies</strong>. You just can&#8217;t get the same thing here. And I want one. Often.</p>

<p>Sigh.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[West Coast State of Mind]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2008/02/20/west-coast-state-of-mind/"/>
    <updated>2008-02-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2008/02/20/west-coast-state-of-mind</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been almost two weeks since I made the move from New Jersey to San Francisco. About thirteen days. Some moments it feels like it&#8217;s been longer and other times it feels like it&#8217;s been no time at all, though admittedly more of the former than the latter.</p>

<p>Now, enough time hasn&#8217;t elapsed where I&#8217;d be able to make sweeping statements of &#8220;west coast attitude vs. east coast attitude&#8221; or anything remotely similar. That&#8217;s not something one can qualify in this short period of time. So much goes into making quality statements like that. Is it a city versus suburbs difference? Is it a California versus New Jersey difference? Is it a hipster versus sub-metro difference? Is it something else? Is it just the ridiculous differences in weather, perhaps!?</p>

<p>What I have learned from my time in this city is that there are many friendly people willing to meet a new face, chat with them, show them around, and have a good time with them. I&#8217;ve met a decently large amount of people in my short time out here, largely in part to the welcoming ways ways of my new housemates and co-workers. Whether or not the welcoming attitude is a personality trait inherent to these fine people or inherent to the region from which they come is something I can&#8217;t determine. Let&#8217;s say it&#8217;s the people.</p>

<p>If you have an open mind and are willing to break &#8212; at least a bit &#8212; from any shell you might be in, moving to a city can be an invigorating experience. I still find myself being a bit hesitant to &#8220;jump in&#8221; in certain respects, but <em>far</em> less so than I thought I&#8217;d be. I&#8217;ve tried new things, changed my eating habits, learned and successfully navigated multiple types of public transportation, gone to several parties and outings, and done some exploring.</p>

<p>Sure, I&#8217;m still wrapped up in a personal cocoon a bit, but it&#8217;s nothing major.  It&#8217;s important to me to maintain my sense of self while learning, experiencing, and taking new aspects for that self. As long as I&#8217;m doing things because I truly want to attempt them or learn about them and not because I feel a social pretext or need to, I will be happy with myself. And, thankfully, there are tons of ways to do that in this new locale.</p>

<p>Work is so far very good. I enjoy the company of my colleagues and feel we are doing well meeting each other. The job is fun and exciting and entails work with technologies I am excited about daily. It is thrilling to work for a variety of clients and brands in the span of a week and to have my work be touched by end users thousands of times over. That I get to balance significant amounts of technical <em>and</em> creative skills in my work is something I&#8217;m very glad about.</p>

<p>Home is becoming more so in rapid chunks of time. It&#8217;s difficult to be engaging and full of energy each day after work, but the relationships I&#8217;m building with housemates and friends are already becoming rewarding and fun. I am comfortable and much sooner than I&#8217;d anticipated. The tiny barriers that exist are all from my own personal end and are sure to be down before long. That, and, getting furniture in my room would go a great distance to making me physically &#8220;set.&#8221;</p>

<p>Missing home is pretty much as I&#8217;d anticipated: it sucks. So many people back home have been very curious about the move and also understanding of any less-than-reasonable time it&#8217;s taken me to get back to them while I get settled. Don&#8217;t let anyone convince you that a three-hour time difference is no big deal &#8212; it is <em>significant</em>. Phone calls, emails, online chats, and any form of communication take on a different timing and sometimes have to juggle two independent contexts that can be so very frustrating. It&#8217;s really limiting and confining in a lot of respects, but I am finding adequate (not great, but adequate) ways around the limitations.</p>

<p>So, in summation: so far, so good. San Francisco has proven itself to be a beautiful, friendly, and fun place to live. Work is fun and challenging at the same time. People are thus far wonderful and welcoming.</p>

<p>I sometimes feel like I&#8217;m still on the way, but in reality I&#8217;m already here.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
