<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Topic: Movies | This is Colin McCloskey]]></title>
  <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/categories/movies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-28T19:40:08-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://mccolin.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Colin McCloskey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movies I Saw From 2010]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/01/02/movies-i-saw-from-2010/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/01/02/movies-i-saw-from-2010</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was not a particularly great movie-going year for me. I just realized that I haven&#8217;t seen a single movie in the thick of the Oscar discussion for the overall picture, director, and actor/actress awards. I&#8217;ve leant strongly toward comedies, which makes this seem a bit of a more base list than I&#8217;d like, but it&#8217;s still worth a recap.</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s a look at all of the movies <em>first released</em> in 2010 that I happened to see &#8212; either in theater or otherwise &#8212; with a rundown of my thoughts. Movies are listed in order by release date.</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leap_Year_(2010_film)"><img class="alignleft" title="Leap Year Poster" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/d/da/Leap_year_poster.jpg" alt="Leap Year Poster" width="125" /></a><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leap_Year_(2010_film)">Leap Year</a></strong><br/>
<em>with Amy Adams, Matthew Goode, and Adam Scott (a personal favorite of mine)</em><br/>
<em>Released to Theaters January 6. Seen on HBO in November.</em><br/>
In most ways, Leap Year, is an utterly predictable and fairly uninteresting romantic/road-trip comedy. Amy Adams is always wonderful to look at and plays the two traits of her role, well. Matthew Goode, who I know very little about, is perfectly great as the Irishman that wins her heart. It&#8217;s upsetting to see Adam Scott playing such a tool, here, but he&#8217;s good at it, and there&#8217;s the quick inclusion of Always Sunny&#8217;s Kaitlin Olsen. Anything that has any amount of Sweet Dee earns a few notches.</p>

<p>This was cutesy and well worth catching on cable. For its positives and generally vanilla lack of negatives, I give it <strong>3 shamrocks of out 5</strong>.</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/8/8a/Crazies_ver2.jpg"><img class="alignleft" title="The Crazies Poster" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/8/8a/Crazies_ver2.jpg" alt="The Crazies Poster" width="125" /></a><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Crazies_(2010_film)">The Crazies</a></strong><br/>
<em>with Timothy Olyphant and Radha Mitchell<br/>
Released to Theaters February 26. Rented from Blockbuster (and subsequently returned late, which they still call me about) in August.</em><br/>
This being a George A. Romero production and a remake of a Romero classic, I had much much much (is that enough muches, yet?) higher hopes for this zombie-like-but-not-quite-zombie movie. There&#8217;s a contamination in the water source turning people in a podunk town all sorts of&#8230; get this&#8230; crazy. And who&#8217;s going to deal with them? The Sheriff, of course. If I&#8217;m being honest, this is a perfectly passable horror movie, with a handful of great scenes and sequences. Plus, there&#8217;s the whole &#8220;figure out if a member of our group is infected&#8221; thing, which is always a mind-bender&#8230; but this ain&#8217;t even a good zombie movie, let alone good movie.</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s to hoping they try harder on the next remake of Romero classic. I give The Crazies <strong>2 out of 5 military containment officers</strong>.</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hot_Tub_Time_Machine"><img class="alignleft" title="Hot Tub Time Machine Poster" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/6/64/Hot_tub_time_machine_poster.jpg" alt="Hot Tub Time Machine Poster" width="125" /></a><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hot_Tub_Time_Machine">Hot Tub Time Machine</a></strong><br/>
<em>with John Cusack, Rob Corddry, Clark Duke, and Craig Robinson. Plus Chevy Chase!<br/>
Released to Theaters March 26. Seen in theater on March 26. And again on HBO recently. </em><br/>
Having now seen this &#8220;film&#8221; for a second time, I can be more objective, but I&#8217;ll start by saying this movie gave moviegoers what it advertised: lots of 80&#8242;s references (both direct and sneaky), lots of stupid 80&#8242;s jokes, and lots of crude, juvenile humor. And you know what? It&#8217;s freaking fun to watch. It&#8217;s not a great time-travel movie. It&#8217;s not a great 80&#8242;s movie, which I suppose it only sort-of is in the first place. On the surface, it makes you feel like John Cusack grabbed some friends to go to the well for some cash, but there&#8217;s enough percolating in here (like everything involving Crispin Glover, the ski patrol kids mistaking the guys for Russian spies, or the many 80&#8242;s movie homages) that make you think it&#8217;s a real effort. And it&#8217;s pretty funny. If you bring your most critical eye, you&#8217;ll find every flaw, but if you sit back and enjoy the ride, you&#8217;ll be cracking up all the way through Rob Corddry&#8217;s Motlue Crue video in the end credits.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s worth a spin. I give it <strong>4 russian energy drinks out of a possible 5</strong>.</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toy_Story_3"><img class="alignleft" title="Toy Story 3 Poster" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/0/0e/Toy_story3_poster3-1-.jpg" alt="Toy Story 3 Poster" width="125" /></a><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Toy_Story_3">Toy Story 3</a></strong><br/>
<em>with the voice talents of Tom Hanks, Tim Allen, and many more including Kristen Schaal!<br/>
Released to the world June 18. <a href="http://lizandcolin.tumblr.com/post/752021107/line-at-movies-in-bakersfield-for-twilight-we">Seen in Bakersfield, CA while moving across the country on June 29</a>.</em><br/>
The verdict on this one seems like it&#8217;s been settled since before or perhaps immediately after it&#8217;s release. Every critic and every fan seems to think this is Pixar&#8217;s finest movie and possibly one of the finest animated feature films ever. While I don&#8217;t disagree that it&#8217;s a great movie, this is not the best animated film ever made. It&#8217;s probably not the best Pixar movie and it may not even be the best Toy Story movie. BUT, all of that said, this is a great movie that &#8212; in true Pixar fashion &#8212; has layers that work for the kids, layers that work for the parents, and layers that work for people like me that are neither of the before stated categories. Seeing this in Bakersfield for something like $6 a ticket was a sweet plus, too! There&#8217;s not much to say that hasn&#8217;t been said, and I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;re familiar with this Toy Story business, already. If you&#8217;ve seen 1 and 2, go see this one. If you haven&#8217;t seen the prequels, check those out and make it a point to see this quite great final chapter.</p>

<p>Give it a look as soon as you find yourself in the mood. <strong>4 and &frac12; potato heads out of 5</strong>.</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knight_and_Day"><img class="alignleft" title="Knight and Day" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/5/51/Knight_and_day_09.jpg" alt="Knight and Day Poster" width="125" height="185" /></a><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Knight_and_Day">Knight and Day</a></strong><br/>
<em>with Tom Cruise and Cameron Diaz<br/>
Released to theaters June 23. Seen in theater in Flagstaff, AZ on July 1.</em><br/>
This movie apparently did not do well in US box office, but recouped expenses and much more internationally. It&#8217;s a shame it didn&#8217;t get seen by more people, because this movie was freaking great. This movie broke my long-lasting dislike of Tom Cruise, though my disdain was crumbling a bit after Tropic Thunder. The stunts, the sights, the love story, the action elements, and generally everything except the old man chewing popcorn loudly near me were great about this movie. I don&#8217;t even typically like Cameron Diaz, but this movie was really fun and exciting. It&#8217;s well-written, well-acted, and has a few great twists to keep you going. If a certain Scott Pilgrim hadn&#8217;t hit theaters later in the summer, this would have easily been the &#8220;funnest&#8221; movie I saw in 2010.</p>

<p>I highly recommend it, regardless of your feelings for or against Tom Cruise. I give it <strong>5 out of 5 motorcycle chases</strong>. Seriously.</p>

<p>I might as well get this out of the way. Despite my best intentions, I did miss the following summer biggies, which I&#8217;d fully hoped to see, during the busy July stretch. I hope to catch them, soon:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Despicable_Me">Despicable Me</a>, July 9. <em>It funny I didn&#8217;t see this, considering how much I quoted it throughout Liz&#8217; and my cross-country trip.</em></li>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Kids_Are_All_Right_(film)">The Kids Are All Right</a>, July 9. <em>I have a soft spot for Mark Ruffalo, but I&#8217;m not sure why.</em></li>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inception_(film)">Inception</a>, July 16. <em>I swear I&#8217;ll see it soon. Nerds, stop chastising me for not having seen it, yet. And stop going on about the new Tron. I won&#8217;t ever see that.</em></li>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dinner_for_Schmucks">Dinner for Schmucks</a>, July 30. <em>It feels like this came out over a year ago with the way it came and went, but it has Steve Carrel, Paul Rudd, AND Jemaine Clement. That&#8217;s a trifecta for me.</em></li>
</ul>


<p><span style="line-height: 24px;">Back to the next (and last) movie from 2010 that I actually did see:</span></p>

<p><span style="line-height: 24px;"><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scott_Pilgrim_vs._the_World"><img class="alignleft" title="Scott Pilgrim vs the World Poster" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/1/14/Scott_Pilgrim_vs._the_World_teaser.jpg" alt="Scott Pilgrim vs the World Poster" width="125" /></a><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scott_Pilgrim_vs._the_World">Scott Pilgrim vs. the World</a></strong><br /> <em>with Michael Cera, Mary Elizabeth Winstead, Jason Schwartzman. Kieran Culkin steals many a scene, as well.<br /> Released in theaters August 13. Seen in theaters on August 13. Then again a week later.</em><br /> In know &#8212; Michael Cera&#8217;s probably worn out his welcome in your household, too. I mean, he&#8217;s always playing the same character and it&#8217;s rarely as likable as good &#8216;ol George Michael Bluth, am I right!? Not so, it turns out. This movie, done by the impeccable Edgar Wright of <em>Hot Fuzz</em> and <em>Shawn of the Dead</em> fame, is a re-imagining of a comic book series that actually draws direct inspiration from the panels on the comic pages. They did cram six full graphic novels into one movie, which leaves some plot lines unfinished and makes you feel it&#8217;s a big frayed around some edges, but the visuals, spot-on reproductions of the comic book characters, and killer soundtrack more than make up for it. Even if Michael Cera is making you queasy these days, you can look past some of his weird mannerisms and concentrate on the hilarious, witty, and fun interpretation of the absurd situations Scott Pilgrim gets into.</span></p>

<p><span style="line-height: 24px;">This movie didn&#8217;t get even make back its budget at the box office, which is a freakin&#8217; shame. Grab the DVD or catch this on Netflix ASAP. I give it a full <strong>5 out of 5 shipments from Amazon.ca</strong>. What&#8217;s the website for that, again?</span></p>

<p>&#8211;</p>

<p>Awesome. The funniest thing about this year may be that I didn&#8217;t see another movie after Scott Pilgrim. I&#8217;ve been cruising through the list and can&#8217;t find another one I did see. There were ones I&#8217;d hoped to see, but I suppose I just didn&#8217;t set my watch to walk up and pay $10 for the &#8220;privilege&#8221; of trying them out.</p>

<p>In September, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Town_(2010_film)">The Town</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Easy_A">Easy A</a> both happened, which I intended to see. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Let_Me_In_(film)">Let Me In</a>, a fun-looking Americanization of <em>Let the Right One In</em>, dropped in October, along with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Social_Network">The Social Network</a>, which is getting all sorts of praise. I missed them all. While I&#8217;m at it, I&#8217;ll point out that I also wanted to see <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nowhere_Boy">Nowhere Boy</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_(2010_film)">Red</a>, but couldn&#8217;t tell when they were coming out form their trailers. Into November, I missed <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harry_Potter_and_the_Deathly_Hallows_(film)">Harry Potter 7</a>, which is pretty radical for someone who has seen all Harry Potter movies within a week of their opening. <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Love_and_Other_Drugs">Love and Other Drugs</a> looked good, but got lost in the holiday season along with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Swan_(film)">Black Swan</a> and that new Disney farce. I will soon enough see <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Fighter_(2010_film)">The Fighter</a> and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/True_Grit_(2010_film)">True Grit</a>, which came out in December, though probably not in that order. They both look spectacular.</p>

<p>So there you have it! A look back at a lackluster year of moviegoing from your&#8217;s truly.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movies I Missed from 2009, Part Two]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/02/02/movies-i-missed-from-2009-part-two/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/02/02/movies-i-missed-from-2009-part-two</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s time, my fair readers, to continue our trip down memory lane. Specifically, memories that I don&#8217;t have of films I never saw from 2009. Without any further ado, I present the continuation (and likely the conclusion) of <strong>Movies I Missed from 2009</strong>, picking up where we left off in August:</p>

<p>In related matters, you may want to <a href="http://mccolin.com/blog/2010/02/01/movies-i-missed-from-2009-part-one" title="Before reading the continuation, you should read the beginning">read the first part of this list</a> before continuing. <em>Now</em> let&#8217;s continue:</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/It_Might_Get_Loud">It Might Get Loud</a> &#8211; August</h3>

<p>I&#8217;m not normally much of a documentary fan (though a few have sparked and held my interest over the years), but this seemed like a good, old-fashioned, awesome time. Comparing and contrasting the careers of Jimmy Page, Jack White, and The Edge with lots of concert and backstage performance material must&#8217;ve been a blast to film and put together for filmmaker Davis Guggenheim, and I&#8217;m certain it&#8217;s a joy to watch and listen to at home. Plans? <strong>Watch on DVD soon</strong>.</p>

<div id="_mcePaste">
  <h3>
    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inglourious_Basterds">Inglourious Basterds</a> &#8211; August
  </h3>
  
  <p>
    This is the 2009 movie that I receive the most flak for not yet having seen. Hands down. I always like a good Tarantino film and was excited for this one&#8217;s release, but never put together a visit to the theater for it. This film has already received its fair share of accolades for its acting, period production, and directing, and will surely be something I snatch up the opportunity to see soon. Plus, my good friend dressed up as Brad Pitt&#8217;s character for Halloween and was appalled I didn&#8217;t pick up on it quickly. Plans? <strong>DVD as soon as I find the time</strong>.
  </p>
  
  <h3>
    <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Fan">Big Fan</a> &#8211; August
  </h3>
  
  <p>
    Patton Oswalt, normally known for his childish and comedic antics, takes a creepy/sad/dramatic turn here as super fan Paul Aufiero, the self-proclaimed &#8220;biggest NY Giants fan in the world.&#8221; He trades barbs with &#8220;Philadelphia Phil&#8221; over a nightly radio broadcast at night, earning his keep as a parking garage attendant by day. When he and his best friend spot their favorite player while out for the night in Statten Island, they follow him and his entourage to Manhattan, where they&#8217;re accused of being stalkers. Oswalt&#8217;s character is beaten within an inch of his life and now must decide on taking legal/criminal action against the best player on his favorite team while dealing with a wide array of family pressures. This movie flew in under the radar, but I&#8217;ve been bent on seeing it since I first checked out the trailer on Apple&#8217;s site. Plans? <strong>I&#8217;m about halfway through it on Netflix Instant right now.</strong>
  </p>
</div>


<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extract_(film)">Extract</a> &#8211; September</h3>

<p>It&#8217;s about that time. Time for Mike Judge to make another film that splits critics and box offices alike. How could this one miss with Jason Bateman, Mila Kunis, JK Simmons, and even Ben Affleck taking turns giving their comedic best? To be perfectly frank, I&#8217;m not even sure what factors move the plot of this movie, but I know that I&#8217;m just more than likely to love anything Judge puts out. Unfortunately for him, I&#8217;m like most everyone else, and won&#8217;t enjoy this one until <strong>DVD</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Informant!">The Informant!</a> &#8211; September</h3>

<p>How was this movie not a huge success!? Matt Damon (who, at this point, is almost always incredible) playing a high-ranking executive turned hilariously bumbling whistle blower already sounds like a farce worth betting on. Plus! Joel McHale plays a pretty decent-sized part. I&#8217;m sold. Still worth tracking down? Yes. And <strong>worth a DVD rental</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Invention_of_Lying">The Invention of Lying</a> &#8211; October</h3>

<p>Ricky Gervais movie. Done. But! A movie set in an alternate reality where everyone tells the truth, except for this one dude (Gervais) who schemes a small lie in a quandary over his rent? Seems plausibly weird and fun. <strong>Worth a look once it hits cable</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whip_It_(film)">Whip It</a> &#8211; October</h3>

<p>So this is a chick flick directed by Drew Barrymore. That sounds like a rough draw, but Ellen Page has stolen movies to success, before, and this just had the feel from its trailers of another good show. A country girl finding her calling in joining a roller derby team that has Kristen Wiig as a member plus as a bonus she has a friend in Maebe Fünke (Alia Shawkat)! Awesome. <strong>May wait for TV or jump on a DVD</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Couples_Retreat">Couples Retreat</a> &#8211; October</h3>

<p>I know. The reviews were bad. The trailer was kind of bad. Vince Vaughn was playing the same character he always does. Jon Favreau hasn&#8217;t done much redeeming work since directing <em>Elf</em>. The deck is stacked hard against this one, but I can&#8217;t let the dream that every Jason Bateman movie is gold die. I&#8217;ll have to see for myself, just <strong>maybe not anytime soon</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/An_Education">An Education</a> &#8211; October</h3>

<p>1960&#8242;s coming of age movies are probably the best type of coming of age movies. That this one is British probably helps it in a few key regards. The sexual and relationship patterns in this movie would be a blast for a psychologist to examine, which I think makes this interesting. <strong>I&#8217;ll catch it on TV</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Where_the_Wild_Things_Are_(film)">Where the Wild Things Are</a> &#8211; October</h3>

<p>It is one of the bigger let downs of my 2009 that I didn&#8217;t make time to see this movie. Everything I&#8217;ve heard is everything you&#8217;ve heard: it&#8217;s a beautiful, poignant, and original take on a cherished children&#8217;s story. They turned 20-or-so pages of illustrated artwork and a few run-on sentences into a full length feature, but didn&#8217;t miss a step. The costumes, scenery, animation, and everything are brilliant. Why didn&#8217;t I skip work to see this one, again!? <strong>Must watch. Quick</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Precious_(film)">Precious</a> &#8211; November</h3>

<p>While October was a pretty good month for movies I missed, gear up for November. <em>Precious</em> starts off the November set with a bang. I think the primary reason I missed this movie is that I was just never set or ready to go see it. It will take a lot out of someone to watch another person be beaten, berated, belittled, and attacked on screen. This is certainly a serious movie with serious material, and word on the street is that it&#8217;s all well done. Mo&#8217;nique is earning favoritism for an Oscar and the star Gabourey Sidibe is fantastic (so say the critics). Sidibe is pretty awesome, too, as she was one of the best guests Conan O&#8217;Brien had this past fall when she was on tour for the movie. <strong>Should see ASAP</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Boat_That_Rocked">Pirate Radio</a> &#8211; November</h3>

<p>I didn&#8217;t know this previously, but <em>Pirate Radio</em> is actually <em>The Boat That Rocked</em>, a British import that was re-cut and re-titled for US release after its critical and box office failure overseas. That cuts this movie down a bit for me, but I&#8217;ve got to say they did a bang up job with the trailers. I&#8217;m sad to read that the movie failed commercially and that it wasn&#8217;t well-received, but still think it looks like a good way to spend a couple hours of my time. <strong>I&#8217;ll probably catch it on Netflix</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fantastic_Mr._Fox_(film)">Fantastic Mr. Fox</a> &#8211; November</h3>

<p>As with <em>Coraline</em> before it in 2009, <em>Mr. Fox</em> aims high with its stop-motion animation and starts with absolutely excellent source material from Roald Dahl&#8217;s original childrens&#8217; book. I&#8217;m a sucker for anything Dahl, but am over a barrel to see this movie with the talents of Wes Anderson behind and Clooney, Streep, Murray, and Schwartzman in front of the camera. Well, their voices, at least. Quick fact: Henry Sellick was co-directing with Anderson on this one until the original studio folded and he left to direct <em>Coraline</em>. That there was early project turmoil is not enough to deter me from <strong>getting this on the Netflix queue as soon as its out</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Messenger_(2009_film)">The Messenger</a> &#8211; November</h3>

<p>This movie follows <em>The Hurt Locker</em> on this list in the military epic class, but attacks the effects on personnel back here at home. Ben Foster plays a soldier who is assigned to work with the Army&#8217;s Casualty Notification service upon returning from tours in Iraq. He pairs with a veteran mentor to the task in Woody Harrelson. While struggling with the mission at hand, a love story develops between Foster&#8217;s character a wife he has notified of her husband&#8217;s death. This movie flew under-the-radar a bit, but has earned great acclaim. That Harrelson appeared in this in the same month as <em>Zombieland</em> is wickedly interesting. <strong>Must see when ready</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Road_(film)">The Road</a> &#8211; November</h3>

<p>Cormac McCarthy&#8217;s novel features life of a man and his son living in a bleak, post-apocalyptic wasteland, scavenging along a great trip south. Along the way, they must avoid cannibals and other obstacles in this dreary life. Viggo Mortensen is a solid actor worth seeing in most anything, and this movie seemed like just the downer of a vehicle to let the dramatic chops fly. I want to see it, but <strong>after reading the book</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brothers_(2009_film)">Brothers</a> &#8211; December</h3>

<p>I saw a trailer for this one night and was immediately hooked. To have Tobey Maguire, of all actors, in the incredibly creepy tormented brother role is a nice twist. Jake Gyllenhaal and Natalie Portman are excellent actors, as well, rounding out the core of a talented cast. In this movie, a family that has moved on after their father (Maguire) goes missing and is pronounced dead in Iraq, hears news that their father is alive and returning home. His wife (Portman) and brother (Gylenhaal) have bonded in the time since he has left and his return dismantles the family that had learned to cope with his loss. Seems like it could have been a tear-jerker, but they crafted it into a psychological thriller&#8230; or I&#8217;m misreading its advertisements. Either way, I&#8217;m in for a <strong>quick Netflix catchup</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crazy_Heart">Crazy Heart</a> &#8211; December</h3>

<p>I&#8217;m going to be totally serious with you on this one. It&#8217;s getting rave reviews and there is Oscar talk abounding for the music and movie. And the main character is The Dude, perhaps better known to most as Jeff Bridges. Having recently re-watched <em>The Big Lebowski</em>, I&#8217;m all in for <em>Crazy Heart</em>, however incomparable those two films are. <strong>DVD only if I can&#8217;t get to a theater soon enough</strong></p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Avatar_(2009_film)">Avatar</a> &#8211; December</h3>

<p>I have *very* mixed feelings about this one. I really had little interest in seeing it. I thought it was going to be stupid and had a heavily recycled plot and maybe too many special effects and not enough substance. Those things may all be true, but the movie has grossed over $2bil and people are still going crazy over it. I&#8217;ve heard (and believe) it must be seen in the theater in 3D, and that&#8217;s probably what I&#8217;ll buckle down and do. I mean, it&#8217;s not going anywhere anytime soon. Verdict? <strong>Theater probably</strong>, if not &#8212; then what?</p>

<p>And that about does it. That&#8217;s my list of Movies I Missed from 2009 &#8212; the movies I wanted to see, but didn&#8217;t get around to for one reason or another. Stay tuned this week for more movie-related list geekery and let me know if you agree, disagree, or have advice for anything based on my list by commenting.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movies I Missed from 2009, Part One]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/02/01/movies-i-missed-from-2009-part-one/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/02/01/movies-i-missed-from-2009-part-one</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I consider myself a fan of movies. Film, even. I like to watch movies. I like to talk about movies. I have an innate ability to &#8220;date&#8221; a movie and tell you its year of release (normally exact, sometimes within a year) just because I seem to keep my ear to the ground when it comes to that sort of thing.</p>

<p>So in the vein of movies, I present to you, dear reader, my first movie list from 2009. Yes, I realize we are now squarely in February of 2010, but these things take time. We&#8217;re coming into awards season full-on with Oscar nominations to be announced tomorrow. My first list, no doubt, includes some likely Oscar noms in it:</p>

<p style="text-align: center;">
  <strong>The Moves I Missed from 2009</strong>
</p>


<p>These are movies I fully intended to see. I really wanted to get to them, either because they looked good in commercial, I&#8217;d read about them online, or they featured actors I love. For some reason or another (laziness, cost-cutting, forgetfulness, inability to drag anyone else along with me, etc.), these are the movies that I never made it to from 2009, in order of release.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coraline_(film)">Coraline</a> &#8211; February</h3>

<p>Dakota Fanning voices a young girl that navigates her way through a surreal and creepy netherworld of sorts&#8230; in full 3D stop-motion animation!? There aren&#8217;t enough movies that aim this high anymore, and the allusions to The Nightmare Before Christmas are many. This was playing in 3D a few places in the city, and I never made it. Verdict? I&#8217;ll be <strong>catching up on DVD soon</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fanboys_(2009_film)">Fanboys</a> &#8211; February</h3>

<p>When the previews sold it accurately as a band of post high school nerds reunited over a plan to break in Skywalker Ranch heading up to the release of 1998&#8242;s The Phantom Menace, I became very excited. A period piece about Star Wars fans with mad cap antics, guest cameos, and all sorts of other fun can&#8217;t go wrong. Then I couldn&#8217;t find it listed anywhere and before too long forgot it had come out in theaters. The film didn&#8217;t do well (and wasn&#8217;t reviewed very well to boot), but there&#8217;s still a part of me that plans to seek this one out. Verdict? <strong>Probably DVD</strong>, maybe catch-up on TV.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sunshine_Cleaning">Sunshine Cleaning</a> &#8211; March</h3>

<p>I think Amy Adams and Emily Blunt can light up the screen, so that&#8217;s excuse enough to see a movie that features both of them. That the producers are those from another well-received movie with &#8220;Sunshine&#8221; in its title (2006&#8242;s Little Miss Sunshine) is another push in the right direction. In the film, the two start a business cleaning crime scenes and learn a lot about their roll in helping others cope with loss. Throughout, they are confronted with their own unresolved feelings regarding their mother&#8217;s suicide. It&#8217;s heavy subject matter with a sunny title, and I&#8217;m still interested. Verdict = <strong>Definitely DVD</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Haunting_in_Connecticut">The Haunting in Connecticut</a> &#8211; March</h3>

<p>This horror movie is based on true events and I&#8217;ve seen enough specials about the house and family in question to know that it&#8217;s some real, serious stuff. A family moves into a former mortuary. That&#8217;s the setting. Add in a gateway to hell, the possession of a son who moves into the basement, and a boatload of creepy imagery and you&#8217;ve put together a pretty adequate horror movie. Now that I think back to this one, I&#8217;m not sure it&#8217;d be worth seeking out, but I&#8217;d stop on the channel for a while should it pop up on TNT or FX in a year. Verdict? <strong>Won&#8217;t try to <em>not</em> see it</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adventureland_(film)">Adventureland</a> &#8211; April</h3>

<p>This has been described to me as &#8220;Superbad without all of the jokes,&#8221; but I&#8217;ve also heard a lot of good things about it from trusted movie-opinionated friends. The key thing is that I&#8217;m a sucker for most movies Ryan Reynolds is a part of (save for Smokin&#8217; Aces&#8230; ugh) and Jesse Eisenberg seems, to me, like Michael Cera if Michael Cera didn&#8217;t get all annoying. So, cool. Verdict? <strong>I&#8217;ll probably Netflix Instant it</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Soloist">The Soloist</a> &#8211; April</h3>

<p>Has anyone before ever resurrected a career the way Robert Downey, Jr. has resurrected his career over the past couple of years? He&#8217;s a personality that really owns a movie when given the chance, and this always looked like a serious movie that was going to happen in. Jamie Fox, we&#8217;ve seen, is surprisingly better in serious roles, and seemed like excellent casting in this drama about a homeless cello prodigy with schizophrenia looking for an opportunity to succeed. That sentence sounded right out of the trailer, just put &#8220;In a world&#8221; in front of it. I tend to catch up on comedy faster than drama, but perhaps this one will get seen soon. Verdict? <strong>Good to go for Netflix Instant</strong> sometime down the line.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Drag_Me_to_Hell">Drag Me to Hell</a> &#8211; May</h3>

<p>As we&#8217;ve already covered, I&#8217;m a sucker for some good horror (see <em>Haunting in Connecticut, The</em>). This movie has the doubly good fortune of being a Sam Raimi flick. Yes, he of The Evil Dead fame. The plot seems about as shabby as you&#8217;d expect &#8212; a banker denies an old lady an extension on her mortgage and is cursed for eternity in response &#8212; but plot&#8217;s not the point. This movie looks like it features a lot of good quick scares, makeup, and visuals that help prop up the lesser plot. And let&#8217;s be honest, that&#8217;s a good enough plot to lean on for a horror movie these days, anyway. Verdict? I&#8217;m sure this <strong>won&#8217;t take long to get to cable</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Taking_of_Pelham_123_(2009_film)">The Taking of Pelham 123</a> &#8211; June</h3>

<p>John Travolta and Denzel Washington, together at last! Yes, this is a remake. And yes, I&#8217;ve heard the original is quite good. But still, seeing John Travolta play the creepy bad guy instead of the heartwarming good guy gives me shivers of 1997 as it gets me thinking of the switcheroo good-guy/bad-guy Travolta from Face Off. Verdict? I&#8217;ll take it all the way to <strong>Netflix, eventually</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Year_One_(film)">Year One</a> &#8211; June</h3>

<p>It&#8217;s important to note this list is just as much as list of movies I *wanted* to see as it is a list of movies I now *want* to see. We&#8217;ve all heard the reviews that slammed this movie as sophomoric and stupid. I am not deaf to these claims, but point out that Michael Cera and Jack Black as cavemen with a guest appearances by McLovin and David Cross can&#8217;t be all that bad. Can it? Maybe it can, now that I think about it. Verdict? I&#8217;ll <strong>catch it on cable</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Hurt_Locker">The Hurt Locker</a> &#8211; June</h3>

<p>Having recently spoken to director Kathryn Bigelow in person (albeit not about this movie, but instead about my crack, on-the-spot, improvised role in a recent showing of <a href="http://www.pointbreaklivesf.com/">Point Break Live</a>), I&#8217;d much like to see this movie. But even before that chance encounter, this movie was something I wanted to give a good look. Military dramas are not often my thing, but this movie is a highly-acclaimed film detailing the painful exposure to war-time situations in Iraq, as well as issues of re-deployment and more. Verdict? <strong>Definite DVD soon</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Public_Enemies_(2009_film)">Public Enemies</a> &#8211; July</h3>

<p>Johnny Depp as John Dillinger. Gunfire. Bank robberies. Explosions. Prison escapes. Excitement. Verdict? <strong>Streamed over the Netflix tubes</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Br%C3%BCno">Brüno</a> &#8211; July</h3>

<p>I don&#8217;t think anyone needs a reason or excuse to see Sacha Baron Cohen performing as any one of his characters. Friends had mixed reviews, but I&#8217;m going to have to see for myself sometime, yeah? Verdict? Can&#8217;t wait for the censored version, so I&#8217;ll have to <strong>Netflix it, but I&#8217;m not in a rush</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orphan_(film)">Orphan</a> &#8211; July</h3>

<p>File this as another &#8220;I&#8217;m a sucker for horror films&#8221; entry. The concept, though it is very <em>The Omen</em>-esque, is just a creepy one. This was heavily advertised, and that&#8217;s either a good thing or a bad thing. Verdict? <strong>I&#8217;ll see it when I see it</strong>, but I will definitely see it.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/District_9">District 9</a> &#8211; August</h3>

<p>This is the movie that every geek was going crazy over this summer. Early in the year, it was <em>Watchmen</em> (stay tuned for that movie&#8217;s appearance in another list of mine), then it was this one. &#8220;Peter Jackson has done it again&#8221; was a frequent comment. The entire concept and its storytelling links to South African Apartheid make this a culturally relevant story worth tracking down, whereas the content and style make it a summer movie worth checking out. The verdict? I&#8217;ll catch it at <strong>home on DVD soon</strong>.</p>

<h3><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Goods:_Live_Hard,_Sell_Hard">The Goods: Live Hard, Sell Hard</a> &#8211; August</h3>

<p>I hate to say it, but Jeremy Piven is becoming less cool to me. He seems like he&#8217;s always playing Ari from &#8220;Entourage&#8221; these days, but then again maybe he always has been. That this movie seems like a cheap remake of one of my all-time favorite comedies, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Used_Cars"><em>Used Cars</em></a>, is another subtraction for this one. However, if this movie gets anywhere near the classic <em>Used Cars</em> in quality or quantity of laughs, it has a lot going for it. I&#8217;m sure to point out that it&#8217;s a different movie, but I&#8217;m still going to see how it stacks up. The verdict? <strong>It&#8217;s in the Netflix Queue</strong>.</p>

<p>&#8230;</p>

<p>The shocking and exciting conclusion to this list is now up! Check out <a href="http://mccolin.com/blog/2010/02/02/movies-i-missed-from-2009-part-two/">Movies I Missed from 2009, Part Two</a>.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll be sure to follow later this week with more 2009 lists, so stay tuned.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
