<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Topic: Meta | This is Colin McCloskey]]></title>
  <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/categories/meta/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-28T19:54:41-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://mccolin.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Colin McCloskey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breathing New Life Into an Old Thing]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2013/12/28/breathing-new-life-into-an-old-thing/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-28T16:59:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2013/12/28/breathing-new-life-into-an-old-thing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So&hellip; it turns out I have a personal website. And you are currently reading it. And it also turns
out that I haven&rsquo;t contributed interesting content to this site &mdash; apart from a résumé update or
two &mdash; since my birthday nearly two years ago.</p>

<p>So&hellip; I&rsquo;ve decided (once again) to put new effort into this place. There are lot of things
going on in my life that are worth talking about &mdash; mostly for my own self reflection purposes, but
no doubt for the benefit of some of you reading. I&rsquo;ve used writing and reflection in the past as
a way to deal with change and challenges and that seems like a good thing for me to be doing as
we head into 2014. <!--more--></p>

<p>What life changes and challenges, you ask!? Well&hellip;</p>

<ul>
<li>I&rsquo;m going to be a dad. <a href="http://thebluesunshine.com/">Liz</a> and I are expecting our first child together, due in early
March of next year. The whole endeavor fills me with joy and excitement, but also questions,
concerns, and worries.</li>
<li>I run <a href="http://awexomelabs.com/">my own solo-employed business</a>. This makes me keen to share thoughts and strategies
for &ldquo;businessy&rdquo; things I&rsquo;m doing.</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m going to be 31 years old, soon, and that means I&rsquo;ll be undeniably <em>in my thirties</em>. This
means I&rsquo;m doing lots more &ldquo;grownup&rdquo; and &ldquo;adult&rdquo; things with my time and my tastes are changing.
That makes for mildly interesting writing, yes?</li>
<li>I&rsquo;m getting into new things like cooking and organizing and projects and more. I think sharing
those things about one&rsquo;s self is important.</li>
</ul>


<p>So, to start, I&rsquo;ve redesigned the site (you are currently using your eyeballs to experience that
change) and <a href="/about/">I&rsquo;ve updated the &ldquo;About Me&rdquo; page on this site</a>. It&rsquo;s got new facts, new stories,
and more than before you can learn about me and my life. And beyond that, I&rsquo;m going to aim to
contribute here more often than I obviously have over the past few years. We&rsquo;ll see if I can keep
up a pace, but the intention is there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shutting the Door, For Now]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/05/18/shutting-the-door-for-now/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/05/18/shutting-the-door-for-now</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I captured all of the contents of articles that were submitted to my favorite website from ten years ago and tucked them behind a locked door. I am, of course, speaking of <strong><a href="http://thosekids.org/fatdog/">fatDOG</a></strong>, the personal website of mine that exploded into an online journal featuring more than 30 authors when I took my first public foray into data-backed website development.</p>

<p>One could almost draw a straight line from the technical things I was playing with at that time (late 2000 to early 2001, for those not keeping track) to the career in which I now call myself a professional.</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://thosekids.org/fatdog/">fatDOG</a></strong> was so much more than that, though. I learned over the years that it was an arena for many of my friends &#8212; and even their friends &#8212; to express themselves in ways they could not afford to anywhere else. Some played with poetry to various degrees of success, others cranked out opinion pieces, and some put together serial stories that remain some of the best writing I&#8217;ve read.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The ways in which this simple website &#8212; a multi-author blog before such a thing was commonplace or simple to do &#8212; touched people are numerous. It touched the authors in a special way, and they were then able to reach out to the readers, sparking conversation about topics as far ranging as love, life, drugs, careers, music, fear, self-doubt, and confidence.</p>

<p>This website captured the emotions of a few dozen people in their late teens and early twenties as they experienced high school graduation, entering college, the September 11th attacks, and the personal battles of college and quarter-life. To this day, it is shocking and fun to read it all back.</p>

<p>So, while I have made the decision to &#8220;lock the door&#8221; on the website as a new annual bill of hosting quickly approaches, I have not and will not lose the key. I will be bringing all of nearly 600 original articles submitted to the website back online in the near future, and asking my contributors to come back for a bit and comment on their thoughts, fears, and work from up to ten years ago.</p>

<p>I can&#8217;t wait to find out what we all think of ourselves when the time comes to look back at the places from which we all came.</p>

<p>To the many authors and readers, friends and lurkers &#8212; you remain the integral part of the favorite thing I have ever built. I encourage you to head over to <strong><a href="http://thosekids.org/fatdog/">fatDOG</a></strong>, now, and review some choice quotes and many of the site&#8217;s famous splash images in the special &#8220;locked&#8221; page that is now up.</p>

<p>Love,</p>

<p>Colin</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>Bask in the history of the fatDOG website at <a href="http://thosekids.org/fatdog/">http://thosekids.org/fatdog/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Things Spambots Blast]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/01/06/the-things-spambots-blast/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/01/06/the-things-spambots-blast</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I don&#8217;t get much in the way of traffic on my blog&#8217;s comments, but always have good &#8216;ol Akismet kicking up lots of spam for me. Normally, it&#8217;s your usual, run-of-the-mill, easily-identifiable sex references, but occasionally it&#8217;s kind of mean. Case in point:</p>

<blockquote><p>I used to love reading your blog, but lately it’s been a little boring. I’ll still read it though =)</p></blockquote>

<p>That&#8217;s harsh, spam robot! I&#8217;ve just started up blogging again and here you go knocking down my self-esteem. I suppose my blog <em>was</em> more original and interesting for the months upon months that I left it dormant. Now that I&#8217;m wasting your time spewing my thoughts into it, it&#8217;s a little hard to take, right? Sorry &#8217;bout that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
