<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Topic: Food | This is Colin McCloskey]]></title>
  <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/categories/food/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-05T13:08:14-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://mccolin.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Colin McCloskey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stuffed Portobello Mushroom Caps]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/10/19/stuffed-portobello-mushroom-caps/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/10/19/stuffed-portobello-mushroom-caps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here I am, at it again! Cooking!</p>

<p>This recipe is a basic, tasty dish that uses a protein I wasn&#8217;t familiar with, personally, but which is a treat to many before me: the portobello mushroom. This dish is one notch away from being vegetarian &#8212; one deliciously wonderful notch. So, you&#8217;re able to modify this to suit a few different dietary needs.</p>

<p>Plus, it&#8217;s frakkin&#8217; delicious and easy to make in about 15 minutes.</p>

<p>You should pick up:</p>

<ul>
<li>Portobello Mushroom Caps &#8212; often sold is a store-wrapped package at your grocer. <a href="http://www.bluefeathermedia.com/index/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/Portobello-Mushroom.jpg">They look like this</a>.</li>
<li>1 tbsp Extra Virgin Olive Oil</li>
<li>1 to 2 Garlic Cloves (depending on how garlic&#8217;y you like things), peeled and minced</li>
<li>1 Red Bell Pepper, cut into strips (you can sub in a green pepper if you&#8217;re stuck, but red or orange peppers are the best &#8212; you should know this already)</li>
<li>Strips of Bacon (one for each mushroom cap)</li>
<li><a href="http://www.mccormick.com/Products/GrillMates/Seasoning-Blends/Grill-Mates-Spicy-Montreal-Steak-Seasoning.aspx">Montreal Steak Spicy seasoning</a> (you can use pepper and red pepper flakes if you want to get close)</li>
<li>Salt (don&#8217;t measure your salt, just go with what feels right)</li>
<li>Shredded Parmesan Cheese (this is a topping, so have enough to top your caps)</li>
<li>Shredded Mozzarella Cheese (also for our cheesy topping)</li>
</ul>


<p>Got it all? Ready to go? Nice. Let&#8217;s continue!</p>

<ol>
<li>Heat the olive oil in a medium skillet over medium heat. Stir in the garlic and peppers. Season with salt. Cook uncovered for a couple minutes, and then&#8230;</li>
<li>Add strips of bacon to the skillet. I find placing them around the edges is best. Continue cooking 2 to 3 minutes until peppers are tender. While tenderizing your peppers&#8230;</li>
<li>Prepare your mushroom caps by first washing them, then drizzle some olive oil on and in the gills (the underside). Season the underside to taste with Montreal Steak (or your pepper substitute) and a bit a salt.</li>
<li>Now, flip the bacon and add your mushroom caps to the center of the skillet, cooking the underside first. Reduce heat to low-medium, cover and cook for about 5 minutes. Your kitchen is going to start smelling really great about now, if it doesn&#8217;t already.</li>
<li>After 5 minutes or so, flip the bacon and mushrooms once more. Layer both shredded cheese on the mushrooms (you are applying the cheese to the seasoned underside of the mushrooms). Cover it up again and cook for another 5 minutes, until tender.</li>
<li>Now it&#8217;s ready! Remove from heat and plate! Take each cheesy mushroom cap off the skillet, then cover each with your pepper/garlic reduction. Put a strip of bacon on top and it&#8217;s good-to-go delicious!</li>
</ol>


<p>It looks like more work than it is. Total prep and cook time should be about 15-20 minutes. And it&#8217;s worth it. The bacon fat helps the peppers and garlic reach a state of &#8220;more awesome than usual&#8221; without robbing the dish of its healthiness.</p>

<p>I suggest you serve beside <a href="http://www.neareast.com/#products/tomato_lentil">Tomato Lentil Couscous</a>, which is a great compliment.</p>

<p>Wow! Colin cooked up mushrooms!</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mom&#8217;s Shrimp Salad]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/07/04/moms-shrimp-salad/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/07/04/moms-shrimp-salad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Perfect for a warm summer day. Not a salad you&#8217;ve added shrimp to, but a chilled pasta and shrimp sensation! Plus, there&#8217;s mayonnaise, so it&#8217;s extra indulgent&#8230; yes, that&#8217;s the word I&#8217;m going for&#8230; indulgent.</p>

<p>You will need:</p>

<ul>
<li>2 cans of Tiny shrimp (Bumble Bee brand is great, substitute Small if your grocer does not have Tiny)</li>
<li>1 lb. box of Medium (or Small) Shell Pasta</li>
<li>1 onion (sweet or not, pick your poison)</li>
<li>Some celery (no exact amount)</li>
<li>Some mayo (again, not exact)</li>
<li>Salt, pepper, spices</li>
</ul>


<p>Take the next 20-30 minutes to prepare, thusly:</p>

<ol>
<li>Cook pasta. This will take about 20 minutes between bringing the water to a boil and the 12-14 minute cooking time. Which is great, because while it&#8217;s cooking, you&#8230;</li>
<li>Dice the onion and celery. Finely diced is best, but this is an inexact science type of dish, so don&#8217;t sweat it.</li>
<li>When ready, drain the pasta, let it cool a bit (don&#8217;t rinse it, just let it cool in your strainer)</li>
<li>Empty the pasta in a big mixing/salad bowl and add salt and pepper to taste. I also sometimes add oregano or light garlic spices, so play with it a bit. Don&#8217;t over-do it, because next you&#8217;ll&#8230;</li>
<li>Add the diced onions and celery.</li>
<li>Open the cans of shrimp, drain the water from them, and add the shrimp to the bowl and mix everything together with a spatula or wooden spoon.</li>
<li>Add mayo. Add it in rounds, you&#8217;d like your component parts to all have some mayo on them, but by no means be covered in the stuff.</li>
<li>Cover the bowl. Chill for a few hours in the fridge.</li>
<li>Remove from the fridge when cold, give it another few stirs and dish it out.</li>
</ol>


<p>You can try this with any type of pasta, but the shells are the best, because they occasionally create these shrimp-onion-celery-pasta bombs in one single bite when they catch everything together. It&#8217;s grand.</p>

<p>This makes me think of my Mom. It makes me think of summer. It makes me happy. It&#8217;s a perfect compliment to burgers, hot dogs, and anything else you&#8217;re whipping up on the grill.</p>

<p>Enjoy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[String Cheese Strategy: Pocket Warmer]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/03/29/string-cheese-strategy-pocket-warmer/"/>
    <updated>2010-03-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/03/29/string-cheese-strategy-pocket-warmer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When eating string cheese, I find that I&#8217;m typically looking for a different flavor experience than when I&#8217;m eating regular-old-mozzarella. Not only is string cheese a &#8220;fun&#8221; cheese that I expect to shred apart with my hands, it&#8217;s a different thing altogether.</p>

<p>What I&#8217;m getting at is&#8230; I like my string cheese warm. Not cold like I prefer balls or slices of mozzarella.</p>

<p>How do I get it warm? I&#8217;m glad you asked. My favorite snack-strategy developed at my new job is the string cheese pocket warm-up. It&#8217;s pretty simple:</p>

<ol>
<li>Grab a string cheese from the fridge</li>
<li>Put it in your pocket (keep it wrapped, please!)</li>
<li>Walk around and talk to a few people.</li>
<li>Get back to work</li>
<li>Then&#8230; remember you have the string cheese in your pocket.</li>
<li>Promptly remove and devour.</li>
</ol>


<p>Wonderful.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Terrible Ideas I&#8217;ve Had: Sour Cream and Onion Cereal]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2009/01/08/terrible-ideas-ive-had-sour-cream-and-onion-cereal/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2009/01/08/terrible-ideas-ive-had-sour-cream-and-onion-cereal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There was a time in my life when I wanted all of my breakfasts to be tasty treats. I went through the Lucky Charms phase (on several different occasions, actually), the Frosted Mini Wheats phase (during which I once exploded in anger like a brat to my Mom because she&#8217;d accidentally bought Frosted Wheat, not Frosted <em>Mini</em> Wheats), the many different varieties of Cheerios phase (including regular Cheerios covered in sugar I&#8217;d add every morning), and more. I was never into the over-the-top, clearly-only-candy-in-disguise cereals (though Cookie Crisp often mesmorized me with that awesome dog in all of their commercials), but I wanted the sweetness.</p>

<p>This love of sweet breakfast foods was combined during early high school years with a desire to combine things I liked into things I thought I&#8217;d really like. That&#8217;s when the madness was born. I wanted, once (just once, I swear) to figure out how to combine oat, potato, sour cream, and onion into a delicious cereal you could enjoy with milk.</p>

<p>Potato Chips? Good! Sour Cream and Onion Potato Chips? Even better! For breakfast!? Oh my god!</p>

<p>It was going to be like a Super Bowl party in your mouth every morning! Or at least that was what the commercials were going to say.</p>

<p>Truth be told, I never investigated the process or the combination of oats and flavorings, so there was never a prototype. Sometimes my mind wanders back to this potential invention and I want to try it&#8230; but then I think better of it.</p>

<p>But be warned if I ever ask you to try &#8220;this awesome new thing&#8221; for breakfast.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cheesy Hot Dog Scramble]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2008/03/23/cheesy-hot-dog-scramble/"/>
    <updated>2008-03-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2008/03/23/cheesy-hot-dog-scramble</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Living on my own in a house with a few other people you&#8217;d think I&#8217;d have all sorts of opportunities to cook and prepare food and learn the ins and outs of the kitchen. Preparing new dishes and making old favorites would become a daily happening, yes? No. I tend to work fairly long hours, grab a bite to eat when I can on my way to or from somewhere else, or whip up something that&#8217;s tried and true &#8212; and pretty standard. Occasionally I stray from old standbys by mixing elements of a few together to make something delicious. Here&#8217;s my first foray.</p>

<p>Now this is not groundbreaking stuff. I&#8217;m probably somewhere between the fourteenth and four-hundred-thousandth person to think this one up, but here&#8217;s how I went about it.</p>

<p><strong>Cheesy Hot Dog Scramble</strong></p>

<p>Ingredients</p>

<ul>
<li>2 Hot Dogs</li>
<li>4 to Six Eggs</li>
<li>Shredded Monterey Jack Cheese</li>
<li>Fresh Ground Pepper</li>
<li>&frac12; Tbsp Butter</li>
</ul>


<p>Preparation</p>

<ol>
<li>Cut the hot dogs into small pieces (as you would for a wee tot) while sizzling the butter to a melt in a frying pan.</li>
<li>Fry up the hot dog bits on the frying pan, flipping them often enough to prevent burning</li>
<li>While frying up the hot dog bits, whisk four eggs with ground pepper and shredded cheese in a small bowl</li>
<li>Remove the hot dogs from the frying pan, <em>leaving the resulting grease in the pan</em>.</li>
<li>Pour the whisked eggs, pepper, and cheese into the pan and prepare as scrambled</li>
<li>When the eggs have coagulated enough, add the hot dog bits and mix all together.</li>
</ol>


<p>Serves two. Delicious on a toasted sandwich or by its lonesome!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
