<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Topic: Heaven | This is Colin McCloskey]]></title>
  <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/categories/heaven/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-06T13:39:49-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://mccolin.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Colin McCloskey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I&#8217;d Like to Think in Heaven&#8230; (#2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2008/12/10/id-like-to-think-in-heaven-2/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2008/12/10/id-like-to-think-in-heaven-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;d like to think that heaven is a place where you have as much time to finish projects you start as you need. There, you feel the adequate amount of pressure required to pull off your projects: never so much as to drive you away and never so little as to let you take forever to finish.</p>

<p>You&#8217;d be free to try new things without feeling silly, unless &#8211; of course &#8211; you like feeling silly when you try new things.</p>

<p>Nothing that should be difficult would be easy, but nothing that should be easy would be difficult. Unless there&#8217;s still something to learn from it. Then it can be somewhat difficult.</p>

<p>In heaven, I don&#8217;t think there are any heating bills.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I&#8217;d Like to Think in Heaven&#8230; (#1)]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2008/03/24/id-like-to-think-in-heaven-1/"/>
    <updated>2008-03-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2008/03/24/id-like-to-think-in-heaven-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;d like to think that heaven is the place where your best dreams come true. If you want to sleep all day, you can. If you want to curl up and watch a movie on a cold, rainy day with your girlfriend and eat grilled cheese and tomato soup, you can. If you want to play Hungry Hungry Hippos or Candyland with your Mom and Dad, you can. If you want to meet some famous or amazing person or family member you never met in life and just hang out all day, you can.</p>

<p>You can do whatever you want. It doesn&#8217;t have to be fancy or perfect. It just has to be comfortable.</p>

<p>Looking back through some old <a href="http://flickr.com/photos/leslieanneforsyth/sets/72057594112606079/" title="Dollar Dogs">photos of my fabulous friend Leslie&#8217;s</a>, I realized I&#8217;ve catalogued thoughts like this, before. Case in point: <a href="http://flickr.com/photos/leslieanneforsyth/132110261/in/set-72057594112606079/" title="Rockin' 305">Rockin&#8217; 305</a>. From early 2006:</p>

<p><a href="http://flickr.com/photos/leslieanneforsyth/132110261/in/set-72057594112606079/" title="Rockin' 305"><img src="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/50/132110261_df5f2f614c.jpg" alt="Rockin' 305" border="0" hspace="5" vspace="5" width="400" /></a></p>

<p>And <a href="http://flickr.com/photos/leslieanneforsyth/132110261/#comment72157594170112137">my comment</a> below it:</p>

<blockquote><p>Dancin&#8217; it up in 305 with a hotdog in my mouth and friends by my side. A duplication of times like this would be a contender on my list of &#8220;things that occur with regularity in heaven.&#8221;</p></blockquote>

<p>I still believe what I said. And looking through those pictures gave me serious pangs of homesickness.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
