<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Topic: Homesick | This is Colin McCloskey]]></title>
  <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/categories/homesick/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-28T19:40:08-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://mccolin.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Colin McCloskey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mom&#8217;s Shrimp Salad]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/07/04/moms-shrimp-salad/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/07/04/moms-shrimp-salad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Perfect for a warm summer day. Not a salad you&#8217;ve added shrimp to, but a chilled pasta and shrimp sensation! Plus, there&#8217;s mayonnaise, so it&#8217;s extra indulgent&#8230; yes, that&#8217;s the word I&#8217;m going for&#8230; indulgent.</p>

<p>You will need:</p>

<ul>
<li>2 cans of Tiny shrimp (Bumble Bee brand is great, substitute Small if your grocer does not have Tiny)</li>
<li>1 lb. box of Medium (or Small) Shell Pasta</li>
<li>1 onion (sweet or not, pick your poison)</li>
<li>Some celery (no exact amount)</li>
<li>Some mayo (again, not exact)</li>
<li>Salt, pepper, spices</li>
</ul>


<p>Take the next 20-30 minutes to prepare, thusly:</p>

<ol>
<li>Cook pasta. This will take about 20 minutes between bringing the water to a boil and the 12-14 minute cooking time. Which is great, because while it&#8217;s cooking, you&#8230;</li>
<li>Dice the onion and celery. Finely diced is best, but this is an inexact science type of dish, so don&#8217;t sweat it.</li>
<li>When ready, drain the pasta, let it cool a bit (don&#8217;t rinse it, just let it cool in your strainer)</li>
<li>Empty the pasta in a big mixing/salad bowl and add salt and pepper to taste. I also sometimes add oregano or light garlic spices, so play with it a bit. Don&#8217;t over-do it, because next you&#8217;ll&#8230;</li>
<li>Add the diced onions and celery.</li>
<li>Open the cans of shrimp, drain the water from them, and add the shrimp to the bowl and mix everything together with a spatula or wooden spoon.</li>
<li>Add mayo. Add it in rounds, you&#8217;d like your component parts to all have some mayo on them, but by no means be covered in the stuff.</li>
<li>Cover the bowl. Chill for a few hours in the fridge.</li>
<li>Remove from the fridge when cold, give it another few stirs and dish it out.</li>
</ol>


<p>You can try this with any type of pasta, but the shells are the best, because they occasionally create these shrimp-onion-celery-pasta bombs in one single bite when they catch everything together. It&#8217;s grand.</p>

<p>This makes me think of my Mom. It makes me think of summer. It makes me happy. It&#8217;s a perfect compliment to burgers, hot dogs, and anything else you&#8217;re whipping up on the grill.</p>

<p>Enjoy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shutting the Door, For Now]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/05/18/shutting-the-door-for-now/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/05/18/shutting-the-door-for-now</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I captured all of the contents of articles that were submitted to my favorite website from ten years ago and tucked them behind a locked door. I am, of course, speaking of <strong><a href="http://thosekids.org/fatdog/">fatDOG</a></strong>, the personal website of mine that exploded into an online journal featuring more than 30 authors when I took my first public foray into data-backed website development.</p>

<p>One could almost draw a straight line from the technical things I was playing with at that time (late 2000 to early 2001, for those not keeping track) to the career in which I now call myself a professional.</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://thosekids.org/fatdog/">fatDOG</a></strong> was so much more than that, though. I learned over the years that it was an arena for many of my friends &#8212; and even their friends &#8212; to express themselves in ways they could not afford to anywhere else. Some played with poetry to various degrees of success, others cranked out opinion pieces, and some put together serial stories that remain some of the best writing I&#8217;ve read.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>The ways in which this simple website &#8212; a multi-author blog before such a thing was commonplace or simple to do &#8212; touched people are numerous. It touched the authors in a special way, and they were then able to reach out to the readers, sparking conversation about topics as far ranging as love, life, drugs, careers, music, fear, self-doubt, and confidence.</p>

<p>This website captured the emotions of a few dozen people in their late teens and early twenties as they experienced high school graduation, entering college, the September 11th attacks, and the personal battles of college and quarter-life. To this day, it is shocking and fun to read it all back.</p>

<p>So, while I have made the decision to &#8220;lock the door&#8221; on the website as a new annual bill of hosting quickly approaches, I have not and will not lose the key. I will be bringing all of nearly 600 original articles submitted to the website back online in the near future, and asking my contributors to come back for a bit and comment on their thoughts, fears, and work from up to ten years ago.</p>

<p>I can&#8217;t wait to find out what we all think of ourselves when the time comes to look back at the places from which we all came.</p>

<p>To the many authors and readers, friends and lurkers &#8212; you remain the integral part of the favorite thing I have ever built. I encourage you to head over to <strong><a href="http://thosekids.org/fatdog/">fatDOG</a></strong>, now, and review some choice quotes and many of the site&#8217;s famous splash images in the special &#8220;locked&#8221; page that is now up.</p>

<p>Love,</p>

<p>Colin</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>

<p>Bask in the history of the fatDOG website at <a href="http://thosekids.org/fatdog/">http://thosekids.org/fatdog/</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pummelvision Made Me Smile]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/12/19/pummelvision-made-me-smile/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/12/19/pummelvision-made-me-smile</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This thing is really fun and useful. I made a Pummelvision based on my Flickr photos, which are admittedly not up-to-date (large chunk missing in the middle), but this was still spectacular to watch. Probably moreso for me than you, but still.</p>

<p>Make your own at <a href="http://pummelvision.com/">pummelvision</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Miss&#8230;]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/04/01/i-miss/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/04/01/i-miss</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some things that pop into mind that I think fondly of, but don&#8217;t currently have&#8230;</p>

<p><strong>I miss driving</strong>. Listening to music possibly too loud while on the way to work. Keeping up with the radio. Just generally controlling my own pace and being able to go beyond the city in which I live. I don&#8217;t miss having to find parking, though.</p>

<p><strong>I miss thunderstorms.</strong> It rains here, but it&#8217;s that weird, unfulfilling, cold rain. Everyone uses umbrellas they don&#8217;t need and nearly poke out my eye as we pass on the sidewalk. And thunderstorms are just cool. I love watching it pour rain outside from under a porch roof in the summer. The smell. Lots of things.</p>

<p><strong>I miss hoagies</strong>. You just can&#8217;t get the same thing here. And I want one. Often.</p>

<p>Sigh.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stuck in Rock City]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2009/06/30/stuck-in-rock-city/"/>
    <updated>2009-06-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2009/06/30/stuck-in-rock-city</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Liz and I are on our way home for a vacation and visit with family. We haven&#8217;t had a length of time back east since Christmas, so we&#8217;ve been looking forward to this for quite some time. It&#8217;d be a lie to say were haven&#8217;t been counting down the days for the past two weeks or so.</p>

<p>So you can imagine we were excited to finally be in the air and on our way this morning. We caught a cab at the crack of dawn (or just before ~5:30) this morning and were waiting for takeoff by five after seven. Certainly an early start for both of us. Well, to be accurate a late night for me, since I hadn&#8217;t (and still as of yet have not) slept. I got a new computer and was otherwise wired, so after packing I played on the computer until the wee hours of cab-time.</p>

<p>The flight was terrible. And that&#8217;s even before I consider that the flight didn&#8217;t even take us where we were supposed to go! I&#8217;m typing this entry from a terminal in a Detroit waiting to figure out when we&#8217;ll be back on our way to New Jersey. Sure, there&#8217;s some prickly weather out there, but it&#8217;s sunny here as I type this.</p>

<p>This is my first time in Detroit. I must say, Gate B5 is a charming site. And the moving walkway to my right is pretty exciting. All-in-all, there&#8217;s a lot to see in Detroit even within the fifty foot radius I&#8217;m allowed to stay while I wait for boarding updates.</p>

<p>Sigh.</p>

<p>Rumor has it they&#8217;re getting things together for us. Maybe we *will* eventually get home, after all!</p>

<p>Until next time, Detroit!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
