<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Topic: Sports | This is Colin McCloskey]]></title>
  <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/categories/sports/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-28T16:07:58-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://mccolin.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Colin McCloskey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Way to Fix the NFL Playoffs]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/01/03/a-way-to-fix-the-nfl-playoffs/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2011/01/03/a-way-to-fix-the-nfl-playoffs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/asset/nfl-logo-footer-2010.png" title="NFL Logo" ></p>

<p>There&rsquo;s a lot of talk&hellip; err&hellip; complaining about the NFL Playoffs. This is mostly because there are a lot of teams with better records than their first-round opponents that will be at a home field <em>dis</em>advantage in the first round, and mostly because there&rsquo;s one team &#8212; the Seattle Seahawks &#8212; who will be hosting a playoff game after a season with a losing record of 7-9.</p>

<p>So here goes.. let&rsquo;s fix this! But fear not &mdash; we won&rsquo;t get too drastic.</p>

<h2>Let&rsquo;s get started in the NFC</h2>

<p>To get us started, let&rsquo;s go over the NFC final standings and playoff seatings, according to current NFL rules:</p>

<ol>
<li>Atlanta Falcons (13-3, winners of NFC South)</li>
<li>Chicago Bears (11-5, winners of NFC North)</li>
<li>Philadelphia Eagles (10-6, winners of NFC East)</li>
<li>Seattle Seahawks (7-9, winners of NFC West)</li>
<li>New Orleans Saints (11-5, wildcard from NFC South)</li>
<li>Green Bay Packers (10-6, wildcard from NFC North)</li>
</ol>


<p>Now, it&rsquo;s worth mentioning that two teams finished with records better than the Seahawks, but did not qualify for the playoffs by virtue of not winning their division. Those unfortunate teams are:</p>

<ul>
<li>New York Giants (10-6, 2nd place in NFC East due to 0-2 record against Eagles)</li>
<li>Tampa Bay Buccaneers (10-6, 3rd place in NFC South behind the Saints and Falcons)</li>
</ul>


<p>Now, it&rsquo;s unfortunate that a 7-9 Seahawks team gets in ahead of those teams, but there&rsquo;s no way a team that wins their division shouldn&rsquo;t get into the playoffs. So, yes, the Seahawks play in a crappy division and the Giants and Bucs play in considerably difficult divisions, but that&rsquo;s the way it goes. You win your division, you get in. And you should.</p>

<p>The problem is that those very same 7-9 Seahawks are actually going to host the far-better-performing 11-5 Saints in the Wildcard weekend, when &#8212; had the Saints been in any other division, they&rsquo;d be waiting at home with a first round bye this coming weekend. That&rsquo;s a tough break for the Saints.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the thing &mdash; if you want a bye, you should have to win your division. Plain and simple. There has to be a prize for winning your division and there has to be a punishment for failing to do so.</p>

<p>BUT, in the Wildcard weekend, all (okay, most) bets should be off. The Saints should be hosting a game, just by virtue of having the best record among the four teams playing in Wildcard weekend.</p>

<p>So here&rsquo;s my plan for re-doing the playoff seating:</p>

<ol>
<li>The four <strong>division winners are in the playoffs</strong>. Your prize for winning a division, even if you do it as crappily as the Seahawks, is that you get to play in the playoffs. This is the same as currently.</li>
<li>The <strong>next best two teams also get in the playoffs</strong>. They didn&rsquo;t win their divisions, but they&rsquo;re freaking good enough to play for a championship. This is also the same as currently.</li>
<li>The <strong>best two division winners have first-round byes</strong>. Settle this with the usual tie-breakers. This would actually keep this year&rsquo;s NFC picture the same as it is, now. Atlanta and Chicago would stay warm and healthy by the fire for the first week of the playoffs. This rule is the same as present. No major changes, yet.</li>
<li>To decide the order of the <strong>wildcard teams, go by best record</strong>, don&rsquo;t initially take division crowns into consideration. This would change the order of the wildcard teams to New Orleans, Green Bay, Philadelphia, Seattle. That&rsquo;s almost a flip-flop. The games would be the same, but the home teams would change.</li>
<li>But! If there is a tie in determining the wildcard seating, <strong>use division championship as the first tie-breaker</strong>. This would mean that though Green Bay and Philadelphia have the same record, and Green Bay has the head-to-head advantage over the Eagles, the Eagles would be seated ahead of the Packers by virtue of winning their division.</li>
</ol>


<p>Now, under these rules, we&rsquo;d see a fairly close seating to what we have, now, but there wouldn&rsquo;t be gross favoritism for division-winning wildcards, only moderate favoritism. If you think about it, a 10-6 Eagles team that was beat in week 1 by a 10-6 Packers team, but was able to win their division when the Packers couldn&rsquo;t, should get home field in that matchup. However, a 7-9 Seahawks team should just be happy <em>to be in the playoffs</em>, and they haven&rsquo;t <em>earned</em> a home playoff game over an 11-5 Saints team that had to battle through a division that could&rsquo;ve easily produced three playoff teams.</p>

<p>So, NFL Competition Committee, I hope you&rsquo;re listening. Here&rsquo;s how the NFC Playoff Standings would shake-down under these new, adjusted rules:</p>

<ol>
<li>Atlanta Falcons (13-3, NFC South Champs, Best Conference Record)</li>
<li>Chicago Bears (11-5, NFC North Champs, First Round Bye)</li>
<li>New Orleans Saints (11-5, 2nd Place NFC South, Best Wildcard Round Record, Home Team for Wildcard Round)</li>
<li>Philadelphia Eagles (10-6, NFC East Champs, Home Team for Wildcard Round)</li>
<li>Green Bay Packers (10-6, 2nd Place NFC North, Visit Philadelphia in Wildcard Round)</li>
<li>Seattle Seahawks (7-9, NFC West Champs, Visit New Orleans in Wildcard Round)</li>
</ol>


<p>That&rsquo;s a lot more stomach-able, yes!? It just makes sense. We shouldn&rsquo;t toss the Seahawks out altogether, because winning your division counts for <em>something</em>, but at 7-9, shouldn&rsquo;t they just be happy to be in the tournament? And under this, the best team in the wildcard round gets a home game. You&rsquo;re welcome, New Orleans Saints.</p>

<h2>How does that shake out in the AFC?</h2>

<p>If you&rsquo;re curious, here&rsquo;s how this would impact the AFC. The AFC breaks down like this under current NFL rules:</p>

<ol>
<li>New England Patriots (14-2, AFC East Champs, Best Overall Record)</li>
<li>Pittsburgh Steelers (12-4, AFC North Champs, First Round Bye)</li>
<li>Indianapolis Colts (10-6, AFC South Champs, Home Wildcard Game)</li>
<li>Kansas City Chiefs (10-6, AFC West Champs, Home Wildcard Game)</li>
<li>Baltimore Ravens (12-4, 2nd Place AFC North, Road Wildcard Game)</li>
<li>NY Jets (11-5, 2nd Place AFC East, Road Wildcard Game)</li>
</ol>


<p>Let&rsquo;s ignore the preposterous fact that the Colts of Indianapolis are somehow in the AFC South division for a second and analyze how the seetings shake out. The Colts and Chiefs <em>both</em> have worse records than the teams they&rsquo;ll <em>host</em> in the wildcard round. Both of them! The Pats and Steelers took care of business, sure, but the Ravens and Jets are getting screwed, here. Under our new seating rules, you&rsquo;d get this:</p>

<ol>
<li>New England Patriots (14-2, AFC East Champs, Home Field Advantage)</li>
<li>Pittsburgh Steelers (12-4, AFC North Champs, First Round Bye)</li>
<li>Baltimore Ravens (12-4, 2nd Place AFC North, Home Wildcard Game)</li>
<li>NY Jets (11-5, 2nd Place AFC East, Home Wildcard Game)</li>
<li>Indianapolis Colts (10-6, AFC South Champs but bad record, Visit New York in Wildcard Round)</li>
<li>Kansas City Chiefs (10-6, AFC West Champs but bad record, Lost tie-breaker to Colts, Visit Baltimore in Wildcard Round)</li>
</ol>


<p>And that is how it should line up. The getting into the playoffs is not the problem. It&rsquo;s the way we&rsquo;re lining up the teams once they&rsquo;re there. A steller Ravens team should not have to go on the road to visit a barely-better-than-mediocre Chiefs team, but the Chiefs belong in the playoffs as the best team in their division, however weak a division it is- and it was pretty weak, this year. When will San Diego put together a full season!?</p>

<p>Likewise, the Seattle Seahawks won their division. It will take a team of NASA scientists and MIT mathematicians to figure out how they won a division with a losing record, but they did do it, so they belong in the tournament. They don&rsquo;t, however, deserve to host the far superior (four wins superior, in fact) New Orleans team in a playoff game.</p>

<p>What say you, NFL Competition Overlords- I mean, Committee!?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cliff Lee makes me happy.]]></title>
    <link href="http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/12/16/cliff-lee-makes-me-happy/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://mccolin.github.io/blog/2010/12/16/cliff-lee-makes-me-happy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cliff Lee makes me happy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
